<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zian &quot;Zane&quot; Liu - Articles</title>
    <description>Synthetic biologist, biomedical engineer, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more...</description>
    <link>
    mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Friends Don’t Let Friends Use Peasant Sticks</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I first used a fountain pen in second grade, but it was only in late 2015 when I picked it up as a “hobby.” Since then, other than for writing on surfaces that absolutely will not tolerate liquid ink, I have seldom picked up a ballpoint or rollerball ink. In fact, I’ve joined some in the fountain pen online community in calling them “peasant sticks” (jokingly, of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, naturally, I’ve started trying to convert my friends to this hobby – my birthday presents to them have shifted from cookies, ties, and pocket squares to fountain pens, almost exclusively. There are a couple fountain pens that I usually get for first time users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;top-pick-jinhao-x750-with-a-custom-nib&quot;&gt;Top Pick: Jinhao X750, with a Custom Nib&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:40.2314814815% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBV-m5Xwikc/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;My new fountain pen came in today! #Jinhao X750 Shimmering Sands with a #Nemosine Extra Fine Nib. #fountainpen #newpen #calligraphy #nib #extrafine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-02-03T23:58:46+00:00&quot;&gt;Feb 3, 2016 at 3:58pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pen that I give as presents the most often is the Jinhao X750, a Chinese-made fountain pen. I like it X750 for two main reasons – it is extremely affordable and still look “fancy.” The “Shimmering Sands” design, pictured above, is especially popular because of the subtle silver glitter on the barrel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key appeal of the X750 is its modularity, and not just because of my training as an engineer. Unlike most modern pens, the X750 comes with a converter, which allows the writer to use bottled ink without dishing out extra cash. In addition, it accepts “standard international ink cartridges,” which means that it will be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/ink-cartridges/c/26/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-long%2CTenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-short&quot;&gt;easy to find refills&lt;/a&gt; for those who favor convenience. Diamine, J. Herbin, Kaweco, Pelikan, and many other ink manufacturers make cartridges that would fit in the X750, meaning that the pen’s user can find a wide variety of color choices without having to subject themselves to the messiness of refilling from a bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the pen’s nib is standard and easy to replace – any “#6 nib” would be able to fit into the pen, which allows the user to change the width and style of their writing. This leads me to one of the drawbacks of the pen – the nib that it comes with is a bit flexible and somewhat bold/thick, which means that it might not be suitable for someone who is trying out fountain pens for the first time. Furthermore, the quality control on these pens tends to be variable. Because of this, I almost always replace the nib with a Fine or Extra Fine from Nemosine or Goulet Pens. This is not only an easier “starting point” for new fountain pen users, but will also show that you put in more time to customize the gift for the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Jinhao X750 is widely available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_from=R40&amp;amp;_trksid=p2050601.m570.l1311.R1.TR5.TRC2.A0.H0.Xjinhao+x750.TRS0&amp;amp;_nkw=jinhao+x750&amp;amp;_sacat=0&quot;&gt;eBay&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/JinHao-X750-Silver-Fountain-Pen/dp/B00CC76756&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt; from Chinese sellers for under $5. You can also find the pen on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-x750/c/97&quot;&gt;Goulet Pens&lt;/a&gt; for slight markup in return for better quality control and, if you’re in the United States, faster delivery. Perhaps somewhat ironic is that replacement nibs will probably run more expensive than the pen itself – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/goulet-replacement-nibs/c/121&quot;&gt;Goulet Pens nibs&lt;/a&gt; run for $15, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/nemosine-nibs-parts/c/537&quot;&gt;Nemosine nibs&lt;/a&gt; $10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;second-choice-platinum-preppy-eyedropper-pen-fine-nib&quot;&gt;Second Choice: Platinum Preppy Eyedropper Pen, Fine Nib&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/preppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Platinum Preppy&quot; title=&quot;Platinum Preppy&quot; /&gt;
More recently, I’ve started giving out Platinum Preppies, which are plastic, refillable but cheap-enough-to-be-disposable fountain pens from Japan. The chief appeal of this pen to me is its nib – a Japanese firm fine steel nib that reliably produces 0.38mm lines. Beginner fountain pen users tend to have an easier time with these firmer, finer nibs, and the Preppy is probably the cheapest pen you can find with that quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, though, Platinum Preppies both look and feel cheap – their bodies are plastic, transparent, and covered in writing. However, these pens are in fact incredibly sturdy. Also, I find that people are more likely to use a Preppy than a fancier, metal pen, simply because the former seems less intimidating, thus facilitating smoother learning and transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good thing about the lack of metal in the pen body is that it can be converted into an “eyedropper,” which means that the entire barrel can be filled with ink if the threading is properly silicone grease-sealed and fitted with an O-ring (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XWLfr7TkRFU&quot;&gt;many tutorials&lt;/a&gt; show how to do this). I estimate that the pen can take around 3mL of ink, which would in turn supply a good 200 pages of writing. I usually eyedropper-convert Preppies before giving them out as gifts – in addition to showing the time and consideration I put into choosing the right ink, the ability to see ink sloshing around in the pen barrel adds novelty to an otherwise plain-seeming pen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Platinum Preppy is easy to find online, and usually come with an ink cartridge. You can usually find them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Platinum-Preppy-Rainbow-Fountain-Point/dp/B00IU3US7O&quot;&gt;rainbow-colored 7-packs from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; for around $15. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-fountain-pens/c/280&quot;&gt;Goulet Pens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andersonpens.com/platinum-preppy-pens-s/1895.htm&quot;&gt;Anderson Pens&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jetpens.com/Platinum-Preppy-Fountain-Pens/ct/371&quot;&gt;JetPens&lt;/a&gt; also sell these pens individually, where they run for around $3-4 each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;third-choice-pilot-metropolitan-fountain-pen-fine-or-medium-nib&quot;&gt;Third Choice: Pilot Metropolitan Fountain Pen, Fine or Medium Nib&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.7685185185% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ3xSfHgZ4j/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Not bad for $15! The Pilot #Metropolitan Retro Pop in #turquoise dots, with a medium nib. #fountainpen #calligraphy #writing #nib #retropop #pilotmetropolitan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-09-02T23:07:43+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 2, 2016 at 4:07pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the fountain pen subreddit and many other online resources, the Pilot Metropolitan tends to be the first fountain pen that beginners buy to get into the habit. In some ways, the pen combines the best qualities of the Jinhao X750 and the Platinum Preppy – it has both an aesthetically appealing metal body and a reliable firm nib (~0.38mm for fine, ~0.5mm for medium). In other ways, it’s pretty much perfect out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why, then, isn’t the Pilot Metropolitan number one on my list? I find that it’s a bit generic for a gift, and the only way you can really “customize” it is to pair it with ink samplers. So, I’d rather have this pen be the first that my friends would later purchase for themselves after becoming more involved in the hobby rather than gifting it to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pilot Metropolitan can be found online (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Collection-Fountain-91111/dp/B00KRPFD96/ref=sr_1_1?s=office-products&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1480137789&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=pilot+metropolitan&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jetpens.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Fountain-Pens/ct/1706&quot;&gt;JetPens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/pilot-metropolitan/c/191&quot;&gt;Goulet Pens&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andersonpens.com/pilot-metropolitan-pens-s/1888.htm?searching=Y&amp;amp;sort=7&amp;amp;cat=1888&amp;amp;show=15&amp;amp;page=1&amp;amp;f-Fountain%20Pen=2448&quot;&gt;Anderson Pens&lt;/a&gt;), and usually sells for $15 for the pen, a cartridge, and a converter. However, if you’re looking to use bottled ink, I suggest buying a twist converter (CON-50 or CON-70), which will add a couple more bucks to the total price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-good-choices&quot;&gt;Other Good Choices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the Jinhao X750, Platinum Preppy, and Pilot Metropolitan, there are definitely more pens that you can buy for friends that you want to bring into the fountain pen hobby. For instance, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-159/c/92&quot;&gt;Jinhao 159&lt;/a&gt; is very similar to the X750, and as a “tribute” to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.montblanc.com/en-us/collection/writing-instruments/meisterstueck/115064-meisterstueck-platinum-line-149-fountain-pen.html&quot;&gt;Montblanc Meisterstück 149&lt;/a&gt;, it looks even more fancy-looking. The Lamy fountain pens are popular alternatives to Pilot Metropolitans, and the brand’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-safari/c/159&quot;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-vista/c/168&quot;&gt;Vista&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-al-star/c/154&quot;&gt;Al-Star&lt;/a&gt; models have triangular grip that show beginner users how to hold their pens in the correct orientation. I, however, never saw the appeal. My handwriting slants to the right, which means that I hold my pens at a different angle. The triangular grip, thus, disrupts my writing more than it helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends don’t let friends use peasant pens – what pens do you give your friends to start them on the hobby?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 10:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/peasantsticks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/peasantsticks</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Is There Such a Thing As Too Much Blue?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the color blue - it’s probably my favorite - and I wear it a lot. I own three solid navy suits and three solid navy sportcoats, most of my dress shirts are in shades of blue or are white with blue patterns, a majority of my ties are blue, and of course I have plenty of blue other accessories. Blue is an easy color to incorporate into any business/classic menswear ensemble, but the ensemble I wore to a departmental banquet tonight got me thinking about whether there’s such a thing as “too much blue.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-LU083_1218ac_GR_20151218152241.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;President Barack Obama&quot; title=&quot;Obama in Tonal Ensemble&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ensemble wasn’t all that uncommon - navy suit, medium blue shirt, and navy dotted tie. In fact, President Obama has started wearing darker shirts in his blue-on-blue ensembles recently, creating an overall “tonal” look, but this doesn’t work quite as well on me. I subscribe to the Alan Flusser’s school of thought that the contrast between a person’s clothing should seek to complement their natural contrast, which means that East Asians like me would look best with higher-contrast ensembles. The suit-shirt-tie combo I wore, however, has very little contrast - practically playing between navy and medium blue. So, while it didn’t necessarily look “bad,” a lighter shirt, or even a patterned one, could have enhanced the ensemble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The low-contrast problem is exacerbated by the fact that the only color in play was blue - a cool color known for its tranquil, peaceful connotations. While good as a base for combining with other colors and patters, wearing an ensemble with too much blue, especially multiple pieces of similar hues, can function to wash out the wearer’s other features and make him supposedly “fade away.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 14:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/toomuchblue</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/toomuchblue</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Fountain Pen Highlighters</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I bought myself some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-highlighters/c/288&quot;&gt;Platinum Preppy highlighters&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of using the free ink cartridges that came with the pen, I eyedroppered them with the matching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gouletpens.com/bottled-ink/c/14/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Brand%3Anoodlers%2CTenant~Ink_Color%3Ahighlighter&quot;&gt;highlighter inks from Noodlers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much, these pens are a hybrid of markers and fountain pens, since it sports the latter’s capillary action ink mechanism and the former’s easy-to-use tip. Filled with water-based yet fluorescent ink, it works quite well, easily drawing emphasis on written documents upon every streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drawback of these highlighters, however, is that it’s quite “wet,” and that the ink can sometimes take awhile to dry atop the page. These properties, desired by users of fountain pens, might not be as useful for highlighters. I’ve had many instances where a too-slow stream with the highlighter not only bled through the back of a page, but stayed on the page long enough to stain the back of the previous page too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I’m satisfied with the Platinum Preppy highlighter. Fountain pen fans should consider getting one to complete their entire fountain pen experience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 05:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/fp-highlighter</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/fp-highlighter</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Happy Fountain Pen Day!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:52.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BMZ7HoFD2Uf/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-11-04T22:30:35+00:00&quot;&gt;Nov 4, 2016 at 3:30pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the first Friday of November, and this means only one thing. Happy National Fountain Pen Day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, why isn’t there a National Pocket Square Day?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 05:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/fountain-pen-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/fountain-pen-day</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Keynote Address at Tau Beta Pi Candidate Meeting</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As prepared for delivery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Zane, and I’m a Master’s Candidate in the Translational Medicine program joint between UC Berkeley and UC San Francisco. As an undergrad here and even now as a grad student, I’ve been really involved in Tau Beta Pi, and I’m here to answer the question, “why am I still here?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just three years ago, I was one of you, attending Candidate Meeting, just one floor up from here in the Woz. I joined TBP at the time because, as I suspect for the same reason many of you are here, I wanted it on my resume, and because I decided that the CM food was good and I wanted more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But ultimately, it wasn’t the prestige or the food that kept me in TBP. I stayed in TBP because, in part, it no longer stood for “Tau Beta Pi” to me; it stood for “the best people,” and I’ll tell you three reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first reason I call TBP “the best people” is that it’s where I found my mentors, and this is an especially surprising statement for me because my interests are very unique – I was a bioengineer who also liked public policy. But you see – Tau Beta Pi is made up of top students from all disciplines engineering and has over 100 years’ worth of alumni who were once those students. So, it’s pretty likely that you can find someone who’s done what you want to do, and could get you where you want to be, even if you’re a special snowflake like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason TBP is “the best people” is that in addition to being mentors, they can also be your references for your next job. I’m learning this after sixteen long years in school and finally starting to look for jobs in the real world. In the job market of today, referrals from an employee might make the difference between getting overlooked or landing an interview. As it turns out, TBP alums can be found in every company you’ll probably consider applying to, and they’re more than happy to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third reason TBP means “the best people” is that in this club, I found lifelong friends. During Veteran’s Day last year, two weeks before my senior project and first set of grad apps were due, I came down with pneumonia. Since I’m a serial procrastinator, I obviously hadn’t worked on my apps, and I tried to convince myself that despite my 104 degree fever, I was fine, and should work on my personal statements. It was a friend that I was only able to meet through TBP who took care of me, offered to bring me soup, and made me stop working and go to the hospital and get diagnosed, treated, and ultimately cured. She’s the reason I’m not only standing before you here tonight as a graduate student in one of the most prestigious translational medicine programs in the world, but also the reason I can stand before you at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBP means “the best people” to me, and clearly, I found value in Tau Beta Pi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you’re here, then you’ve been recognized as one of the best engineers in one of the finest universities in the world. All of you will succeed, regardless of whether you have the line “Tau Beta Pi” on your resume, but I encourage you to come and explore what TBP has to offer you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I found my mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I found my references.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I found my closest friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be around after, hopefully somewhere in the front of the food line outside, if you have any questions about what I just said. You’ll also find me at as many free food events this semester as I could make, and I hope that I’ll meet each and every one of you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 13:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/cm</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/cm</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Cabinet Reshuffles</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was President of the Bioengineering Honor Society, I remember wishing for the power to “reshuffle cabinet.” This is a common practice amongst heads of government, such as prime ministers in parliamentary democracies and the President of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple – the President or PM has the power to assign people in his cabinet to new official positions. This could be used to promote political allies or demote political rivals (which is probably the most common reason for reshuffles), or simply to optimize the governmental utility, putting the people with the most expertise or interest in each area in the positions that have influence on them. In a student group, this can work similarly – the President, or some constitutionally determined “executive,” can “move” officers around between positions. This can be appealing for two reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason is that new club members don’t always run for and get truly fitting positions; as these new officers get to know the club more, they may discover other roles which are more “appropriate” for their interests and talents, and a cabinet reshuffle allows them to enter that more appropriate portfolio instead of being “stuck” in their current one, without having to wait months for another election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason has to do with time – many officers discover halfway through their term that they are too busy with their schoolwork to perform their expected tasks. A cabinet reshuffle, in this case, can allow busy officers and less-busy officers to swap positions, allowing both to remain a part of the club while allowing work to get done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are, of course, counterarguments to implementing reshuffling. While promotions from favoritism may be a concern, I argue that it will likely be less prevalent than in government. Being offered some club title and, in conjunction, all the responsibilities associated with it, is not nearly as attractive as being offered the position of being third-in-line to the Presidency, and the social backlash will be high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another potential drawback of reshuffling is that members may not be as willing to become an officer if they don’t have the guarantee of being able to stay. Admittedly, some people are more driven by a position profile than the club when they run to be an officer (e.g. running to be an industrial relations position to get recruiter contacts, without much regard for the actual club). However, if an officer were so interested in their work, they should do well in it, and thus not need to be “reshuffled” to another position. So, this concern should be minimal as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student clubs need flexibility among their personnel. More clubs should consider allowing their officers to move around – through cabinet reshuffles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 05:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/cabinet-reshuffles</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/cabinet-reshuffles</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Tieless Suit</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Presidents Xi of China and Obama of the United States met yesterday at the Sunnylands Estate in California. The dress code of the event was “no ties,” to emphasize the casual and friendly nature of the talks, but both leaders still chose to wear conservative solid navy suits and white shirts. (Photo: Evan Vucci, AP)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 11:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-tieless-suit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-tieless-suit</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How Wide Should Ties Be?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Some ties can compete with spaghetti strands with respect of width, while other ties look more like napkins. I’ve seen ties from 1 inch to 5 inches. Ties both extremely wide and extremely narrow look comical when worn by common folk, but somehow, there are people who can magically pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 11:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/how-wide-should-ties-be</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/how-wide-should-ties-be</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Moving Into Luxury Inks</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BItjdn2gc1c/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-08-05T03:23:06+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 4, 2016 at 8:23pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 12:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/luxury-inks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/luxury-inks</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dimple Your Tie!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, technically, it’s a choice, but really, do dimple your tie.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 12:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/dimple-your-tie</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/dimple-your-tie</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>My First Fountain Pen</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometime in elementary school (for me, it was second grade), every Chinese kid would need to switch from writing with pencil to writing with a fountain pen - in every class. In addition to teaching us to write neatly, writing with a fountain pen was supposed to instill in us the value of doing things correctly the first time around. After all, ink, unlike graphite, was permanent, and showed our mistakes. So, if crossed-out sections or evidence of mysteriously ripped-out pages were found in our noteboks, we would be called up to the front of the class and berated for all to see.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 09:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/first-fp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/first-fp</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>No Longer Eat Alone</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I wrote this essay in the beginning of my Freshman year of college. Now that I’m about to graduate, I’m posting this again for reflections.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 23:06:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/no-longer-eat-alone</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/no-longer-eat-alone</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Rice 360 Design Competition</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;My undergraduate biodesign team, Team ForSight, was invited to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rice360.rice.edu/#!design-competition/wv2xp&quot;&gt;Rice 360° Sixth Annual Undergraduate Global Health Technologies Design Competition&lt;/a&gt;. My team mates, Amanda and Ian, and I presented our design for a drug-eluting contact lens targeted for use in developing countries, to deliver antifungal drug natamycin to treat corneal ulcers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/rice-360</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/rice-360</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bioweapons Departmental Seminar at the MIIS</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;By the invitation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miis.edu/academics/faculty/rzilinskas&quot;&gt;Dr. Ray Zilinskas&lt;/a&gt;, I spoke at a departmental seminar at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.miis.edu/&quot;&gt;Middlebury Institute of International Studies&lt;/a&gt; today, where I presented my research on the impacts of recent technological advances on the biosecurity landscape. I was the first undergraduate to ever be invited and to speak at such a seminar at MIIS, a graduate-only institution.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 04:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/miis-seminar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/miis-seminar</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Brooks Brothers No. 1 Stripe</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/-zEkcqQig3/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-12-02T17:34:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Dec 2, 2015 at 9:34am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 09:34:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/bb-no-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/bb-no-1</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Bulletin of the Atomic Scietists - Bioweapons... for Dummies?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;My article on the threat of amateur biohacking on the national security landscape was published on the Bulletin of the Atomic Scietists today, in the “Voices of Tomorrow” column.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-bulletin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-bulletin</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Can I Wear a Button-Down Collar With a Tie?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/7IpJkDwig7/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2015-09-02T16:32:46+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 2, 2015 at 9:32am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 03:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/button-down-with-tie</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/button-down-with-tie</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Presidential Address to 2015 BioEHSC</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My speech at the opening ceremonies of the 2015 Bioengineering High School Competition, as prepared for delivery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, and welcome to the second annual Bioengineering High School Competition, hosted by BioEHS at UC Berkeley!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Bioengineering Honor Society, we strive to advance bioengineering, both within UC Berkeley and in the community beyond. This effort begins with strengthening our membership, through workshops, networking events, and job and research opportunities. It continues with fostering the community, through service events and hosting the largest study group program on campus. And it culminates with events like this one - reaching out to elementary, middle, and high school students such as yourselves - and showing that as long as you have talent, as long as you have drive, as long as you want to solve problems in biology, you can be a bioengineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say this knowing that bioengineering is not easy. It’s not supposed to be. To solve problems in human health and medicine, biology simply is not enough. Bioengineers must learn more to gain the set of tools needed to combat these concerns - from chemical engineering to patent engineering and from computer science to political science - but having knowledge isn’t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bioengineers must be undertake more responsibility because the subject of our work is not only chemicals and computers, but humans and other living things. The goal of our efforts is not just to save time or material, it is to save lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are challenges that come with this responsibility - FDA regulations, concerns in bioethics, societal impacts - nuances that may slow your progress. It will take longer for a bioengineer to succeed, but when you do, you feel a greater accomplishment. You are rewarded with not only wealth and fame, but also the knowledge that your efforts touched another human life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsibility. Character. Knowledge. These are some of the qualities of a successful bioengineer. Throughout today’s events, you will meet many of them - famed academics, researchers young and old, budding entrepreneurs, among others - and hear their perspectives on why bioengineering was right for them. After today, I hope you will gain a better understanding of what bioengineers do and what a career in biotechnology is like, and I hope that some of you will see the value that bioengineering holds for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your outcome in this competition, I hope you find this event informative, and fun too. Regardless of which career path you later pursue, I hope that you will take today as an opportunity to meet and network with all the competitors gathered here - nearly 80 of you and with more on their way, because the next generation of the world’s leadership lie within people like you. Talk to each other; learn from each other; exchange ideas; help each other make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we, here at BioEHS, will continue to work to bring more events like this to more young leaders just like you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time, and let the bioengineering begin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 01:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/bioehsc</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/bioehsc</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BioEHS President Inaugural Address</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I am honored and humbled to assume the Office of President of the Bioengineering Honor Society. For myself and on behalf of this club, I want to thank my predecessor for all she has done.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 12:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/inauguration-address</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/inauguration-address</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>On Open Collars</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/tieless.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tieless at an outreach event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2013 13:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/on-open-collars</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/on-open-collars</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Few Words on Socks</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not an expert on socks, but I know enough to not wear white athletic socks with my suits and black dress shoes. I even know not to wear black dress socks unless I’m wearing black trousers (which is a rare occurrence in the first place). Instead, a man’s dress socks should help connect one’s clothing to his shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 13:13:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/a-few-words-on-socks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/a-few-words-on-socks</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Last Well Dressed President</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;President Obama wears a uniform of dark blue or charcoal suits with white or light blue medium-spread barrel cuff shirts and darker ties. The suits are mostly well-cut from Hart Schaffner Marx, a traditional American clothier, but they still look off-the-rack. Overall, President Obama looks just like another businessman – conservative and better than many of his poorly-dressed colleagues in Washington, but nothing special.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 03:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-last-well-dressed-president</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/the-last-well-dressed-president</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dress Shirts that Every Man Should Own</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Though I often find reasons to justify my own dress shirt purchases, I have to admit: for a person who doesn’t plan to wear a dress shirt on a regular basis and instead only for designated “business” or “business casual” events, two dress shirts are sufficient – a plain white dress shirt with a medium-spread collar and barrel cuffs and a light blue button-down.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 17:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/dress-shirts-that-every-man-should-own</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/dress-shirts-that-every-man-should-own</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Buttoning a Suit</title>
        
          <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 18:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/buttoning-a-suit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/buttoning-a-suit</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Some Thoughts on Black Suits</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The black suit is becoming increasingly popular among men. From President Vladimir Putin of the Russian Federation to Hollywood starts to peasants on Chinese farmer’s markets, the black suit now seems everywhere. In Asia, black has replaced navy blue and charcoal gray as the standard color for men. Even in the Americas, Men’s Wearhouse has gone as far as telling customers that the black suit is the “first and only suit” that most men need.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>
        mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/on-black-suits</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com/on-black-suits</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
