<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>zane@chairmanzian.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
   <description>Synthetic biologist, biomedical engineer, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more...</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Suiting Up for Interviews</title>
	  <link>//interview</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-14T08:34:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//interview</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s interview season for me, which means that for the first time in a while, I’ll be wearing a suit by necessity, not by choice. Certainly, dressing up frequently implies that I’ll probably be more comfortable with this “elevated formality” when compared to most of my peers, “interview attire” still is a little different from my personal style.</p>

<p>When I wear a suit for an event, I tend to pay attention only to coordination between different garments. This, when done with a general preference for subtle patterns and high contrast usually would yield very British-inspired ensembles – quiet suits and ties, patterned shirts, and an bright-colored pocket square. With respect to shoes, I alternate between pairs of longwing brogues in different shades of burgundy and brown. They not only provide a sense of sophistication, but also are easy to find well-cared-for, vintage, and affordable on eBay.</p>

<p>If I were to show up in these ensembles for an interview, I doubt I’ll raise any eyebrows (maybe if I wear my signature hot pink pocket square, it might be another story…). Even so, I still tend to err even more conservative, following the tried-and-true mantra of “two solids and a stripe.”</p>

<p>This, coupled with conservative business colors, only yields a few options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A worsted woolen suit in solid navy or dark/charcoal gray.</li>
  <li>A cotton shirt in solid white or light blue</li>
  <li>A silk tie in burgundy or a shade of blue, with stripes (or some other small, conservative pattern)</li>
  <li>Black leather belt and shoes, preferably oxfords</li>
</ul>

<p>Pretty simple, right? Yes – if you have the luxury of having a wardrobe that has all these pieces, or the time and resources to buy or borrow them, but I’ve learned that most of my peers do not. How does one, then, make do with the pieces you have?</p>

<h3 id="suit">Suit</h3>
<p>Probably the biggest limiting factor. Solid blue or gray suits are ideal, but I find that a lot of my friends would instead own black suits (a cardinal sin in men’s business dress, mind you – read my first blog article), or some multi-striped monstrosity on sale at Men’s Wearhouse. My judgment aside, wear the darkest, least-patterned suit you have. If you must choose between a solid black suit and some multi-stripe with a more conservative color, go with the solid black – you can likely pass it off as navy or charcoal on a cursory glance.</p>

<h3 id="shirt">Shirt</h3>
<p>You really should have a solid white shirt and a solid light blue shirt. In addition to that, for interviews, you’d want a shirt that is well-fitting, has either a point or moderately-spread collar, and uses barrel cuffs. If this is not available, a button-down or wider spread collar should also work, but I’d avoid any shirts that has French cuffs – they might be seen as a “power play” garment. If you don’t have a “solid color” shirt, wear the one you have with the lightest background (preferably white) and least amount of patterns (no more than one additional color, in a simple stripe or checkered pattern).</p>

<p>Oh, another addition – I recommend against wearing a blue shirt against a black suit – the contrast just doesn’t look right. Blue suit and gray suits are, on the other hand, will be far more “forgiving.”</p>

<h3 id="tie">Tie</h3>
<p>Probably the most flexible part of this ensemble, but nonetheless still limited by the need to remain simple and “business-like.” A blue somewhere between royal and navy or a darker shade of red or burgundy works best, and I would find one with a small repeating pattern (pin-dots work well) or stripe, and stick away from solids because they are a tad “too” boring. A gray tie could work, but lighter shades or “silvers” might make you seem like you’re going to a wedding rather than an interview. Follow the rules on pattern sizing if any of your other garments are also patterned (match different patterns and vary like patterns).</p>

<p>I would be cautious, though, on wearing colors that are too “flashy” – that’s the bright reds, purples… anything that you would find on POTUS 45. On a similar note, stay away from shiny ties – a bit of sheen is good, but for interviews, you’d want to look more like POTUS 44 than the current one.</p>

<h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and Socks</h3>
<p>Nothing much to say here – wear black leather dress shoes and a matching leather belt. If you don’t have that, wear your darkest leather shoes or sneakers, and hope that your interviewer doesn’t look down. Your socks should match your pants, and if that doesn’t work, your shoes, and your ankle should be covered always. At no time is it appropriate it wear white, athletic socks, to a business formal interview…</p>

<p>If you have the luxury of choose, or are in the process of buying shoes, consider the following. Lace-up styles are better than slip-on loafers, and closed lacing systems (like Converse, but leather) are seen as more appropriate than open lacing. In addition, choose plain styles over complex patterns (e.g. brogues), and avoid overly square or overly pointy toe styles.</p>

<p><strong>And that’s it! These are all the pieces you’ll need to dress for an interview. Good luck!</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Reconsider the Three-Button Suit</title>
	  <link>//reconsider-3b</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-12T05:32:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//reconsider-3b</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Once upon a time, not too long ago, men were expected to wear three-button suits – it’s just how things were, and in fact, JFK was considered a “radical” for opting for two-buttons during his presidency. Even in recent memory, two-button and three-button jackets were seen at similar frequencies, and considered “equally appropriate” for occasions of the same formality. However, three-button suits are now hard to find. When I visited a Hickey Freeman store last summer, I was surprised to hear that the maker no longer carried ready-to-wear three-button models, and that the style was only available made-to-measure.</p>

<p>Why did this formerly revered style disappear? All other things equal, a two-button suit will probably “more forgiving,” flattering more body types than its three-button equivalent, as well as feeling “less restrictive” when buttoned up. Even so, I still have a soft spot for the three-button style – and not just because I’m a “snowflake millennial from California” who likes to be different. A three-button coat, worn correctly, can work wonders to make a man look taller and slimmer.<br />
<img src="http://icanstyleu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/sometimesalwaysnever.jpg" alt="Sometimes, always, never" />
The biggest “mistake” that I see on three-button suit wearers is fastening the buttons improperly – and this is an easy fix. As a reminder, the “rule” for such a suit is “sometimes, always, never,” from the top button down. To this, I propose a revision that the top button on a three-button coat should be closed “almost never.” This way, your three-button jackets looks virtually identical to a two-button, thus getting all its benefits. In addition, the presence of a third button could help you look taller – thank physics for visual illusions!</p>

<p>What, then, is the problem with buttoning both top buttons? On most such jackets, fastening the top button will leave almost no “space” between the lapels to “display” the shirt and tie, making the entire top half of the ensemble seem out of proportion. The lapels themselves will probably seem too short and too wide, all contributing to make the wearer seem short and stout and “misshapen” as well (Michel Anton’s words, not mine).</p>

<p>In what cases, then, can you safely button the top two buttons? This “style” works best on tall, skinny folks – on whom the proportions of a closed three-button suit would seem more reasonable. A suit with a lower top button, thus leaving more room to display the tie, and with narrower lapels, as to better “scale” the rest of the ensemble, would also help make the “top two” buttoning style make sense.
So, with that, go try on some three-button suits! If you could find one, that is.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Why I Got Into Suits</title>
	  <link>//why-suits</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-06-26T15:52:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//why-suits</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>If you walk through Berkeley, you will probably see more people in hoodies and sweatpants rather than jackets and ties. So, as a menswear enthusiast based in the Bay Area, I frequently get questions about what got me into suits and ties. So, I figured I’d write about this here.</p>

<p>Growing up, I spent a lot of time with my grandpa. As a former high school principal, Grandpa was accustomed to projecting authority through his clothes, and a wardrobe to match. Specifically, I remember he had four separate suits. The first, bought for cheap, was the suit he wore for going shopping to the open-air farmer’s market. The second, slightly more upscale, was for going to supermarkets (i.e. the indoor ones) and picking me up from school. A third suit would be for “general use,” such as photos, greeting guests, and attending social functions. The last suit was reserved for “special occasions only.” A 60th birthday gift from his children, the suit was from China’s then-top-designer and had a sticker price worth a few months of an average man’s salary. When I asked Grandpa to show it to me the last time I was back in Beijing, he informed me that the suit was safely locked away in a suitcase, and will only be brought out “when the occasion is right.”</p>

<p>However, I liked sweats and hated shopping as much as any other kid. It was an eye surgery during high school that finally exposed me to the more “respectable” parts of the menswear spectrum. After the procedure, doctors warned me to avoid pulling garments over the eye. This meant for a month post-surgery, I could only wear button-ups – I was forced to explore what I could do with them, and the habit eventually became stuck. I found that I was beginning to wear collared shirts by choice, rather than simply to protect my eye.</p>

<p>To make things arguably worse, I soon discovered the world of “thrifty menswear,” a community of men who seek treat purchasing menswear with the same attitude some have towards cars – “let someone else absorb the cost of buying new!” After all, quality, well-maintained suits or ties should last for decades. Furthermore, frequent sales and deals could bring the cost of new garments close to that of a “club fundraiser” t-shirt. As a result, my wardrobe grew, and we all know what happened next. Today, I own over 50 ties, write my own fashion blog, and teach workshops telling engineers how to dress for an interview.</p>

<p>Interesting how things go, isn’t it?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>What Color Tie Should I Wear?</title>
	  <link>//whatcolortie</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-03-14T14:45:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//whatcolortie</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Picking a tie can be difficult – they come in so many different colors, not to say different shades within the same color. Even between two ties of the exact same color, the texture of each fabric may come into play in figuring out which tie looks best with the rest of one’s ensemble.</p>

<h3 id="its-all-about-contrast">It’s all about contrast</h3>

<p>The traditional ideology picking color tones/shades is that the suit is darker than the tie, which is in turn darker than the shirt. This rule works, but really shouldn’t be taken that seriously. While “suit darker than shirt” is a tried-and-true rule, the interplay between other garments is more flexible, and can best be summarized as “contrast or exact match.”</p>

<p>This statement might sound a bit confusing at first – if two things either match or contrast, then… what are they? In essence, you should avoid wearing colors that are similar but not the same – for example, a white shirt with a pale-yellow tie or a navy suit with a dark-but-not-yet-navy blue tie. Why is this a problem? Think back to the last time you had to insert figures into PowerPoint. You were using a white template and your figure looked like it had a white background too, but once you overlaid them, you found that the two “whites” were different. Now there was an awkward, faint border around your figure – not contrasting enough to look intentional and just enough to be annoying.</p>

<p>Get the image now? Try to avoid that in what your wear.</p>

<h3 id="fill-in-the-colors">Fill in the colors!</h3>
<p><img src="https://www.sessions.edu/wp-content/themes/divi-child/color-calculator/color-wheel.png" alt="A color wheel" />
It’s hard to come up with a definitive rule of what colors work well together and what don’t. Other than the rules that black should mix with neither navy nor brown, most colors will work with each other. (Even navy/brown and black can be worn together tastefully.) You can use color wheel to find the best tie colors to contrast or harmonize with a given jacket or shirt, but let’s be honest – it will take forever.</p>

<p>If you’re lazy, you can wear colors that are known to work: blue and gray, blue and red or orange, purple or pink with navy or black, blue or purple and yellow, brown and tan, etc. An easy way to figure out what “works” is to see what combinations exist in nature – colors found in scenery, on plants, in insects or animals. I admit it might sound weird at first, but just think about it – when was the last time you described nature as “awkward?”</p>

<p>A “more advanced” technique is to have one garment match the secondary color in another garment. What does that mean? If you’re wearing a suit with blue stripes, a tie with the same color as the stripe seems to be a logical next step. The color of your hair or your eyes is another place of “inspiration. For instance, former Vice President Biden was frequently praised by stylists for wearing blue ties that matched the color of his eyes.</p>

<h3 id="want-to-stop-thinking-about-it">Want to stop thinking about it?</h3>
<p>Prefer the Mark Zuckerberg/Steve Jobs aesthetic of wearing essentially the same thing every day? There’s a way to do that with suits too. Solid navy and solid burgundy ties work with pretty much every suit and every shirt, and with that, you now have more time to worry about everything else going on in your life.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Acceptance Speech, Fall 2016 TBP Member of the Semester Award</title>
	  <link>//mots-acceptance</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-12-02T11:34:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mots-acceptance</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>As prepared for delivery.</em></p>

<p>Thank you. This means a lot to me.</p>

<p>I’ve never been a man of few words, so today is certainly not the time to start.</p>

<p>For those of you who made it to candidate meeting, you might remember that I said I stuck around in TBP because it no longer stood for Tau Beta Pi to me, but for “the best people.” Hopefully, after this semester, this sounds less like a corny attempt at a pun and more like something true.</p>

<p>I hope that this semester, through Tau Beta Pi, you met someone new who you would now wave to when you see each other on campus.</p>

<p>I hope you met someone who you now trust enough to work together, or even carry you through, a group project.</p>

<p>I hope you met someone who you will now go to for advice.</p>

<p>I hope you met someone who you can see someday helping you find a job.</p>

<p>And I hope you met someone who you’ve gotten closer to outside of TBP. Someone whom you would now consider a new friend. Because, in the end of the day, when you are as old as I look, what will matter most to you from Tau Beta Pi is not the line on your resume, or that GEICO discount, or even the scholarships and fellowships, but the people.</p>

<p>And because of that, this award both means so much, and feels a bit unnecessary.</p>

<p>It has been my pleasure, and will always be my pleasure, to spend time around the best people – my fellow Tau Bates, like you.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Friends Don’t Let Friends Use Peasant Sticks</title>
	  <link>//peasantsticks</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-25T10:06:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peasantsticks</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I first used a fountain pen in second grade, but it was only in late 2015 when I picked it up as a “hobby.” Since then, other than for writing on surfaces that absolutely will not tolerate liquid ink, I have seldom picked up a ballpoint or rollerball ink. In fact, I’ve joined some in the fountain pen online community in calling them “peasant sticks” (jokingly, of course).</p>

<p>So, naturally, I’ve started trying to convert my friends to this hobby – my birthday presents to them have shifted from cookies, ties, and pocket squares to fountain pens, almost exclusively. There are a couple fountain pens that I usually get for first time users.</p>

<h3 id="top-pick-jinhao-x750-with-a-custom-nib">Top Pick: Jinhao X750, with a Custom Nib</h3>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:40.2314814815% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BBV-m5Xwikc/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">My new fountain pen came in today! #Jinhao X750 Shimmering Sands with a #Nemosine Extra Fine Nib. #fountainpen #newpen #calligraphy #nib #extrafine</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-02-03T23:58:46+00:00">Feb 3, 2016 at 3:58pm PST</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>The pen that I give as presents the most often is the Jinhao X750, a Chinese-made fountain pen. I like it X750 for two main reasons – it is extremely affordable and still look “fancy.” The “Shimmering Sands” design, pictured above, is especially popular because of the subtle silver glitter on the barrel.</p>

<p>Another key appeal of the X750 is its modularity, and not just because of my training as an engineer. Unlike most modern pens, the X750 comes with a converter, which allows the writer to use bottled ink without dishing out extra cash. In addition, it accepts “standard international ink cartridges,” which means that it will be <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/ink-cartridges/c/26/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-long%2CTenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-short">easy to find refills</a> for those who favor convenience. Diamine, J. Herbin, Kaweco, Pelikan, and many other ink manufacturers make cartridges that would fit in the X750, meaning that the pen’s user can find a wide variety of color choices without having to subject themselves to the messiness of refilling from a bottle.</p>

<p>Even the pen’s nib is standard and easy to replace – any “#6 nib” would be able to fit into the pen, which allows the user to change the width and style of their writing. This leads me to one of the drawbacks of the pen – the nib that it comes with is a bit flexible and somewhat bold/thick, which means that it might not be suitable for someone who is trying out fountain pens for the first time. Furthermore, the quality control on these pens tends to be variable. Because of this, I almost always replace the nib with a Fine or Extra Fine from Nemosine or Goulet Pens. This is not only an easier “starting point” for new fountain pen users, but will also show that you put in more time to customize the gift for the recipient.</p>

<p>This Jinhao X750 is widely available on <a href="http://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_from=R40&amp;_trksid=p2050601.m570.l1311.R1.TR5.TRC2.A0.H0.Xjinhao+x750.TRS0&amp;_nkw=jinhao+x750&amp;_sacat=0">eBay</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JinHao-X750-Silver-Fountain-Pen/dp/B00CC76756">Amazon</a> from Chinese sellers for under $5. You can also find the pen on <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-x750/c/97">Goulet Pens</a> for slight markup in return for better quality control and, if you’re in the United States, faster delivery. Perhaps somewhat ironic is that replacement nibs will probably run more expensive than the pen itself – <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/goulet-replacement-nibs/c/121">Goulet Pens nibs</a> run for $15, and <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/nemosine-nibs-parts/c/537">Nemosine nibs</a> $10.</p>

<h3 id="second-choice-platinum-preppy-eyedropper-pen-fine-nib">Second Choice: Platinum Preppy Eyedropper Pen, Fine Nib</h3>
<p><img src="assets/images/preppy.jpg" alt="Platinum Preppy" title="Platinum Preppy" />
More recently, I’ve started giving out Platinum Preppies, which are plastic, refillable but cheap-enough-to-be-disposable fountain pens from Japan. The chief appeal of this pen to me is its nib – a Japanese firm fine steel nib that reliably produces 0.38mm lines. Beginner fountain pen users tend to have an easier time with these firmer, finer nibs, and the Preppy is probably the cheapest pen you can find with that quality.</p>

<p>Admittedly, though, Platinum Preppies both look and feel cheap – their bodies are plastic, transparent, and covered in writing. However, these pens are in fact incredibly sturdy. Also, I find that people are more likely to use a Preppy than a fancier, metal pen, simply because the former seems less intimidating, thus facilitating smoother learning and transition.</p>

<p>Another good thing about the lack of metal in the pen body is that it can be converted into an “eyedropper,” which means that the entire barrel can be filled with ink if the threading is properly silicone grease-sealed and fitted with an O-ring (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XWLfr7TkRFU">many tutorials</a> show how to do this). I estimate that the pen can take around 3mL of ink, which would in turn supply a good 200 pages of writing. I usually eyedropper-convert Preppies before giving them out as gifts – in addition to showing the time and consideration I put into choosing the right ink, the ability to see ink sloshing around in the pen barrel adds novelty to an otherwise plain-seeming pen.</p>

<p>The Platinum Preppy is easy to find online, and usually come with an ink cartridge. You can usually find them in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Platinum-Preppy-Rainbow-Fountain-Point/dp/B00IU3US7O">rainbow-colored 7-packs from Amazon</a> for around $15. <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-fountain-pens/c/280">Goulet Pens</a>, <a href="http://www.andersonpens.com/platinum-preppy-pens-s/1895.htm">Anderson Pens</a>, and <a href="http://www.jetpens.com/Platinum-Preppy-Fountain-Pens/ct/371">JetPens</a> also sell these pens individually, where they run for around $3-4 each.</p>

<h3 id="third-choice-pilot-metropolitan-fountain-pen-fine-or-medium-nib">Third Choice: Pilot Metropolitan Fountain Pen, Fine or Medium Nib</h3>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.7685185185% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ3xSfHgZ4j/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">Not bad for $15! The Pilot #Metropolitan Retro Pop in #turquoise dots, with a medium nib. #fountainpen #calligraphy #writing #nib #retropop #pilotmetropolitan</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-09-02T23:07:43+00:00">Sep 2, 2016 at 4:07pm PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>According to the fountain pen subreddit and many other online resources, the Pilot Metropolitan tends to be the first fountain pen that beginners buy to get into the habit. In some ways, the pen combines the best qualities of the Jinhao X750 and the Platinum Preppy – it has both an aesthetically appealing metal body and a reliable firm nib (~0.38mm for fine, ~0.5mm for medium). In other ways, it’s pretty much perfect out of the box.</p>

<p>Why, then, isn’t the Pilot Metropolitan number one on my list? I find that it’s a bit generic for a gift, and the only way you can really “customize” it is to pair it with ink samplers. So, I’d rather have this pen be the first that my friends would later purchase for themselves after becoming more involved in the hobby rather than gifting it to them.</p>

<p>The Pilot Metropolitan can be found online (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Collection-Fountain-91111/dp/B00KRPFD96/ref=sr_1_1?s=office-products&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1480137789&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=pilot+metropolitan">Amazon</a>, <a href="http://www.jetpens.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Fountain-Pens/ct/1706">JetPens</a>, <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/pilot-metropolitan/c/191">Goulet Pens</a>, <a href="http://www.andersonpens.com/pilot-metropolitan-pens-s/1888.htm?searching=Y&amp;sort=7&amp;cat=1888&amp;show=15&amp;page=1&amp;f-Fountain%20Pen=2448">Anderson Pens</a>), and usually sells for $15 for the pen, a cartridge, and a converter. However, if you’re looking to use bottled ink, I suggest buying a twist converter (CON-50 or CON-70), which will add a couple more bucks to the total price.</p>

<h3 id="other-good-choices">Other Good Choices</h3>
<p>Besides the Jinhao X750, Platinum Preppy, and Pilot Metropolitan, there are definitely more pens that you can buy for friends that you want to bring into the fountain pen hobby. For instance, the <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-159/c/92">Jinhao 159</a> is very similar to the X750, and as a “tribute” to the <a href="http://www.montblanc.com/en-us/collection/writing-instruments/meisterstueck/115064-meisterstueck-platinum-line-149-fountain-pen.html">Montblanc Meisterstück 149</a>, it looks even more fancy-looking. The Lamy fountain pens are popular alternatives to Pilot Metropolitans, and the brand’s <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-safari/c/159">Safari</a>, <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-vista/c/168">Vista</a>, and <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-al-star/c/154">Al-Star</a> models have triangular grip that show beginner users how to hold their pens in the correct orientation. I, however, never saw the appeal. My handwriting slants to the right, which means that I hold my pens at a different angle. The triangular grip, thus, disrupts my writing more than it helps.</p>

<p>Friends don’t let friends use peasant pens – what pens do you give your friends to start them on the hobby?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Is There Such a Thing As Too Much Blue?</title>
	  <link>//toomuchblue</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-21T14:06:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//toomuchblue</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I love the color blue - it’s probably my favorite - and I wear it a lot. I own three solid navy suits and three solid navy sportcoats, most of my dress shirts are in shades of blue or are white with blue patterns, a majority of my ties are blue, and of course I have plenty of blue other accessories. Blue is an easy color to incorporate into any business/classic menswear ensemble, but the ensemble I wore to a departmental banquet tonight got me thinking about whether there’s such a thing as “too much blue.”</p>

<p><img src="https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-LU083_1218ac_GR_20151218152241.jpg" alt="President Barack Obama" title="Obama in Tonal Ensemble" /></p>

<p>My ensemble wasn’t all that uncommon - navy suit, medium blue shirt, and navy dotted tie. In fact, President Obama has been wearing darker shirts in his blue-on-blue ensembles recently, creating an overall “tonal” look, but this doesn’t seem to work quite as well on me. I subscribe to the Alan Flusser’s school of thought that the contrast within a person’s clothing should seek to complement their natural contrast, which means that East Asians like me would look best with higher-contrast ensembles to go with the yellow skin and black hair. The suit-shirt-tie combo I wore, however, has very little contrast - practically playing between navy and medium blue. The low-contrast problem is exacerbated by the fact that the only color in play was blue - a cool color known for its tranquil, peaceful connotations. While good as a base for combining with other colors and patters, wearing an ensemble with too much blue, especially multiple pieces of similar hues, can function to wash out the wearer’s other features and make him supposedly “fade away.”</p>

<p>So, while my ensemble didn’t necessarily look “bad,” a lighter shirt, or even a patterned one, could have enhanced it. A tie with a bit more contrast - possibly with broader white stripes rather than the less conspicuous dots - would have also done the trick. I did try to add as much contrast as possible with my pocket square by wearing one with a black and white houndstooth, which I thought would provide both pattern and difference in color, but, looking back, a square with slightly more white probably would have worked better.</p>

<p>Blue in all of its shades are great colors for menswear, but be wary of overusing it. Careful management of contrast is necessary to prevent blue ensembles from fading away.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Fountain Pen Highlighters</title>
	  <link>//fp-highlighter</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-05T05:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fp-highlighter</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Recently I bought myself some <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-highlighters/c/288">Platinum Preppy highlighters</a>. Instead of using the free ink cartridges that came with the pen, I eyedroppered them with the matching <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/bottled-ink/c/14/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Brand%3Anoodlers%2CTenant~Ink_Color%3Ahighlighter">highlighter inks from Noodlers</a>.</p>

<p>Pretty much, these pens are a hybrid of markers and fountain pens, since it sports the latter’s capillary action ink mechanism and the former’s easy-to-use tip. Filled with water-based yet fluorescent ink, it works quite well, easily drawing emphasis on written documents upon every streak.</p>

<p>The drawback of these highlighters, however, is that it’s quite “wet,” and that the ink can sometimes take awhile to dry atop the page. These properties, desired by users of fountain pens, might not be as useful for highlighters. I’ve had many instances where a too-slow stream with the highlighter not only bled through the back of a page, but stayed on the page long enough to stain the back of the previous page too.</p>

<p>Overall, I’m satisfied with the Platinum Preppy highlighter. Fountain pen fans should consider getting one to complete their entire fountain pen experience!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Happy Fountain Pen Day!</title>
	  <link>//fountain-pen-day</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-04T05:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fountain-pen-day</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:52.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BMZ7HoFD2Uf/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-11-04T22:30:35+00:00">Nov 4, 2016 at 3:30pm PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>It’s the first Friday of November, and this means only one thing. Happy National Fountain Pen Day!</p>

<p>On that note, why isn’t there a National Pocket Square Day?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Keynote Address at Tau Beta Pi Candidate Meeting</title>
	  <link>//cm</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-22T13:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//cm</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>As prepared for delivery.</em></p>

<p>I’m Zane, and I’m a Master’s Candidate in the Translational Medicine program joint between UC Berkeley and UC San Francisco. As an undergrad here and even now as a grad student, I’ve been really involved in Tau Beta Pi, and I’m here to answer the question, “why am I still here?”</p>

<p>Just three years ago, I was one of you, attending Candidate Meeting, just one floor up from here in the Woz. I joined TBP at the time because, as I suspect for the same reason many of you are here, I wanted it on my resume, and because I decided that the CM food was good and I wanted more.</p>

<p>But ultimately, it wasn’t the prestige or the food that kept me in TBP. I stayed in TBP because, in part, it no longer stood for “Tau Beta Pi” to me; it stood for “the best people,” and I’ll tell you three reasons why.</p>

<p>The first reason I call TBP “the best people” is that it’s where I found my mentors, and this is an especially surprising statement for me because my interests are very unique – I was a bioengineer who also liked public policy. But you see – Tau Beta Pi is made up of top students from all disciplines engineering and has over 100 years’ worth of alumni who were once those students. So, it’s pretty likely that you can find someone who’s done what you want to do, and could get you where you want to be, even if you’re a special snowflake like me.</p>

<p>The second reason TBP is “the best people” is that in addition to being mentors, they can also be your references for your next job. I’m learning this after sixteen long years in school and finally starting to look for jobs in the real world. In the job market of today, referrals from an employee might make the difference between getting overlooked or landing an interview. As it turns out, TBP alums can be found in every company you’ll probably consider applying to, and they’re more than happy to help you out.</p>

<p>The third reason TBP means “the best people” is that in this club, I found lifelong friends. During Veteran’s Day last year, two weeks before my senior project and first set of grad apps were due, I came down with pneumonia. Since I’m a serial procrastinator, I obviously hadn’t worked on my apps, and I tried to convince myself that despite my 104 degree fever, I was fine, and should work on my personal statements. It was a friend that I was only able to meet through TBP who took care of me, offered to bring me soup, and made me stop working and go to the hospital and get diagnosed, treated, and ultimately cured. She’s the reason I’m not only standing before you here tonight as a graduate student in one of the most prestigious translational medicine programs in the world, but also the reason I can stand before you at all.</p>

<p>TBP means “the best people” to me, and clearly, I found value in Tau Beta Pi.</p>

<p>Now, if you’re here, then you’ve been recognized as one of the best engineers in one of the finest universities in the world. All of you will succeed, regardless of whether you have the line “Tau Beta Pi” on your resume, but I encourage you to come and explore what TBP has to offer you.</p>

<p>This is where I found my mentors.</p>

<p>This is where I found my references.</p>

<p>This is where I found my closest friends.</p>

<p>I’ll be around after, hopefully somewhere in the front of the food line outside, if you have any questions about what I just said. You’ll also find me at as many free food events this semester as I could make, and I hope that I’ll meet each and every one of you there.</p>

<p>Thank you.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
