<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>chairmanzian@gmail.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:chairmanzian@gmail.com</link>
   <description>Synthetic biologist, bioengineer, biosafety advocate, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Tieless Suit</title>
	  <link>//the-tieless-suit</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-09T11:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-tieless-suit</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="http://globalbalita.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Barack-Obama-and-Xi-Jinping-summit-2013.3.jpg" alt="Xi Obama Sunnylands" />
<em>Presidents Xi of China and Obama of the United States met yesterday at the Sunnylands Estate in California. The dress code of the event was “no ties,” to emphasize the casual and friendly nature of the talks, but both leaders still chose to wear conservative solid navy suits and white shirts. (Photo: Evan Vucci, AP)</em></p>

<p>Wearing a suit without a tie can cause controversy. Proponents of the look call it “executive casual,” referring to the ensembles preferred by company executives who do not need to conform to a dress code, but still wish to look elevated. Critics, however, dub the look “the Ahmadinejad,” referring to the unpopular former Iranian President, whose country forbids the wearing of a tie due to the garment’s implications of Western oppression.</p>

<p>For a long time, I was not a huge fan of wearing a suit without a tie. After all, it makes no sense why anyone would bother putting on matching jackets and trousers if he considers tie as too inconvenient. Aesthetically, though, there’s really no reason why a sport jacket and odd trousers could be worn tieless and a suit cannot. So, lately, I’ve been finding myself doing the exact same thing that I attacked viciously just years ago - putting on a suit, checkered shirt, and a brightly-colored pocket square, but leaving the tie at home.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-we-wear-ties-anyways">Why Do We Wear Ties Anyways?</h3>
<p>To remove a tie from an ensemble, it is first important to understand the purpose of a necktie. In addition to filling up the space below one’s neck and above the lapel, the necktie also serves to add color, slim the body, and provide so-called “balance” to the ensemble by “tying an ensemble together.”</p>

<p>For example, if I were to wear a navy suit and a white shirt, wearing a tie of another color would reduce the starkness of the contrast between the two colors, making the ensemble more pleasant-looking. Even a navy tie can serve to enhance the ensemble, for it will reduce the amount of white color displayed to reduce the amount of contrast seen.</p>

<h3 id="leaving-the-tie-at-home">Leaving the Tie At Home</h3>
<p><img src="http://cdn.abclocal.go.com/images/kgo/cms_exf_2007/news/state/9161881_1280x720.jpg" alt="Gavin Newsom" />
<em>Lt. Gov. Gavin Newsom wears a lighter gray suit for an open-collar shirt. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)</em></p>

<p>To accomplish the “executive casual” look, one should consider toning down the contrast between suit and shirt to trivialize the tie’s purpose of “tying together an ensemble.” One can do so by wearing a lighter colored suit (e.g. light gray and tan) or wearing a darker-colored and/or patterned shirt (solid white bad!). Also, one should consider choosing a suit with little “tie space” (higher buttoning point) to begin with, such as a more modern two-button or a three-button-roll. Note that though double-breasted and three-button suits tend to have smaller tie spaces, the suits tend to be more formal, and thus unsuitable for executive <em>casual</em>.</p>

<p>Some stylists suggested against the button-down collar for this look because the colloar is inherently casual and not sufficiently <em>executive</em> for “executive casual.” Instead, they would recommend a spread collar, which can stand upright without a tie and has uppity implications.</p>

<p>Stylists also warned against pinstripe suits due to their so-called formality, but I find no basis for their concerns because the pinstripe suit is not <em>formal</em>, but rather <em>for business</em>. Instead, I think the pinstripe suit is perhaps even ideal for this role - the stripes can both add color and serve a slimming and lengthening effect, both of which are usually the role of a tie. I would also add that the charcoal or dark gray suit should be avoided completely - both colors are too boring and too formal for executive casual.</p>

<p>Don’t forget a pocket square for a finishing touch!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>How Wide Should Ties Be?</title>
	  <link>//how-wide-should-ties-be</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-07T11:32:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//how-wide-should-ties-be</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Some ties can compete with spaghetti strands with respect of width, while other ties look more like napkins. I’ve seen ties from 1 inch to 5 inches. Ties both extremely wide and extremely narrow look comical when worn by common folk, but somehow, there are people who can magically pull it off.</p>

<p>There are two criteria that determine tie width – body width and lapel width. Those wider in the chest should wear wider ties, while those on the skinnier side should keep to narrower ties. This rule keeps one’s body and clothing within proportion.</p>

<h3 id="the-rule-of-thumb">The Rule of Thumb</h3>
<p><img src="https://blacklapel.com/thecompass/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/tiewidth_v7.png" alt="Tie width diagram" />
<em>Image from BlackLapel.com</em></p>

<p>But, unless you wear only custom-tailored ties, it will be hard to find ties that suits one’s proportions exactly. Instead, the width of a tie is usually chosen to match the lapel – the widest point of the tie should measure about the same as the widest point of the jacket lapel.</p>

<p>3.25 inches is a common width for lapels on recent suits, and 3.5-4 inches is more common for suits made in the 90s and early 2000s. Most ties on the market today around 3 inches in width, while 3.75 inches was considered standard for older ties.</p>

<h3 id="additional-considerations">Additional Considerations</h3>
<p><img src="http://blog.trashness.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/sorley-knit.jpg" alt="Peak Lapel with Knit Tie" />
<em><a href="http://ethandesu.com/post/21772396846/sorley-knit-and-orazio-peaks">Source</a></em></p>

<p>Peak lapels, with “peaks” pointing up towards the shoulders, can generally be worn with ties a bit narrower than its width, because the viewer’s attention is not directed at the tie. With notch lapels, however, one can err towards wider ties (although narrow ties work too). Even so, keep difference in width between lapel and tie within half an inch, if possible. Any larger width difference creates discord and looks extremely absurd.</p>

<p>Lastly, the composition of a tie also matters in tie width. Ties with “interesting” (read “distracting”) patterns and weaves (such as wool knits, silk knits, and grenadines) need less width to “grab attention.” So, ties with intricate designs, either in fabric or in pattern, are allowed to be narrower than the jacket lapels. For the same reason, smoother, non-catchy ties can be slightly wider without causing too much trouble.</p>

<h3 id="a-final-word">A Final Word</h3>
<p>I used to be very particular in matching the width of jacket lapels and ties -  I even did a bit of sewing work on some particularly wide (~4 in) ties so I could wear them with slimmer suits, but ultimately, it wasn’t worth it. The visual improvement was minimal, since I was an amateur at sewing, I destroyed the lining on some of the ties I “modified,” resulting on them being unwearable.</p>

<p>If your jacket lapels are within an inch of the width of your tie, you’re probably fine.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Dimple Your Tie!</title>
	  <link>//dimple-your-tie</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-02T12:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//dimple-your-tie</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Well, technically, it’s a choice, but really, do dimple your tie.</p>

<p>In ties, a dimple is an indentation of the tie’s fabric formed directly below the knot. It is a common mark of a well-tied tie. The dimple can both complement a symmetrical knot (e.g. half-Windsor, Windsor) and add balance to an asymmetrical knot (e.g. the four-in-hand).</p>

<p>I dimple all my ties. It’s not particularly hard, especially when I use a thicker tie (e.g. wool, silk knits) or one over 3 inches wide. In the last step of forming the knot before tightening, I pinch the side of the tie with my thumb and middle finger while pressing down on the center with my index finger. The dimple forms, as a result, wherever the index finger presses.</p>

<p>Many well-dressed individuals wear their ties with a dimple, but a dimple is by no means a definitive feature of a well-tied tie. A dimple is nice, but it shouldn’t be forced. On skinny ties, a dimple is difficult or impossible to create simply because there isn’t sufficient fabric in the tie to provide for one. Also, dimples are often hard to maintain on thinner, softer fabrics. If you’re wearing one of those ties, and you cannot form a dimple by pressing on the middle of the tie below the knot, don’t “force” it by over-tightening the knot. The dimple is meant to be a natural occurrence, at best created with a little guidance. If your tie really doesn’t want to dimple, it probably was never meant to do so in the first place.</p>

<p>For the same reason, don’t worry too much about the number of dimples or its (their) location(s). Unless you’re using a half-Windsor or Windsor knot, both of which demand centered, symmetrical dimples, the location of the dimple doesn’t really matter. A dimple of any kind will be sufficient to give “balance” to the ensemble.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Brooks Brothers No. 1 Stripe</title>
	  <link>//bb-no-1</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-12-02T09:34:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//bb-no-1</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/-zEkcqQig3/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2015-12-02T17:34:39+00:00">Dec 2, 2015 at 9:34am PST</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>There are few ties that scream “America” as much as the Brooks Brothers #1 Repp - the first in a series of striped ties that define the essence of Brooks Brothers (and Ivy League) style. The #1 Repp has a series of 5 stripes, alternating in two colors, that run from the top right to the bottom left (the “American way”), widely spaced on a solid background. The <a href="http://www.brooksbrothers.com/BB%231-Repp-Tie/0210,MA02076,default,cp.html?dwvar_A230_Color=BURG&amp;contentpos=39">“original” version</a> is suitable for wear with solid or striped shirts, and the <a href="http://www.brooksbrothers.com/Mini-BB%231-Repp-Tie/0210,MA02077,default,cp.html?dwvar_193A_Color=BLCK&amp;contentpos=27">“mini” version</a> may pair better with solids and medium-sized plaids and checks.</p>

<p>Despite it perhaps being best-known as BB #1, the bar stripe tie is by no means exclusive to Brooks Brothers. I’ve seen many clothing companies make their own versions of the BB #1. J Press sells a design very similar to the Mini BB #1 at a similar price range and quality. In fact, President <a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/cd/43_George_H.W._Bush_3x4.jpg">George H.W. Bush</a> wore it for his official portrait. Jos. A. Banks calls its version as “Trapped Bar Ties.” Though they retail at a price range similar to that of Brooks, Jos A Banks’ frequent sales makes the tie a suitable lower-quality replacement.</p>

<p>For more fashion-forward individuals, J Crew will occasionally offer similar-looking ties such as this “Triple Stripe” in cotton. For those who spend by the penny, The Tie Bar’s $15 “Bar Stripe” and even some ties offered by Target’s Merona could disguise themselves as the famed BB #1 Repp. I snatched both of mine from the local Goodwill store for $5 each. Since the design of the BB #1 hasn’t changed for years, the ties are indistinguishable from newly-bought ones other than their being a quarter-inch wider at the base.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Can I Wear a Button-Down Collar With a Tie?</title>
	  <link>//button-down-with-tie</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-09-02T03:58:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//button-down-with-tie</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/7IpJkDwig7/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2015-09-02T16:32:46+00:00">Sep 2, 2015 at 9:32am PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>The short answer is yes; <strong>as long as you wear a four-in-hand, you can wear button-down collar dress shirts with a tie</strong>.</p>

<p>The longer answer gets a bit complicated.</p>

<p>The button-down collar has casual roots – it was originally found on British polo shirts. It was brought back to the United States and placed on button-down shirts by Brooks Brothers. The “Polo Button-Down,” as it was named, was designed to be a sport shirt – the buttons would serve to prevent the collars from flapping when a tie isn’t worn.</p>

<p>The button-down-with-tie look was created a bit after, and was first seen in the early 20th century on Ivy League students. These students wore the then-casual shirt with blazers and striped/emblem ties that represented club membership, and as these men moved on past college, the button-down-with-tie look became an integral part the American workplace.</p>

<p>With that said, it is not hard to see that the button-down-with-tie look would be inappropriate both with more European clothing and in events requiring traditional and more formal attires. Here’s a few instances where it should never be worn.</p>

<ul>
  <li>With a black suit. Black suits are too formal for the inherently casual collar. Additionally, American menswear makers do not usually make black suits – a tradition that honors President Abraham Lincoln, who was killed in such a suit.</li>
  <li>With a black tie (unless knit), also due to disagreements in formality.</li>
  <li>To an event demanding “evening informal” or greater formality.</li>
</ul>

<p>Here are things to avoid:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Plain, solid ties (especially satin). These ties are extremely formal and should only be worn with more formal shirts. Textured solid weaves, such as the grenadine, silk knit, and shantung, are more than acceptable.</li>
  <li>Ties with stripes running from the upper left to lower right (heart to sword). These ties are called “British Stripe.” Many elements of American menswear were made to be complete opposites of British styling, and the two should not mix.</li>
  <li>Any “business formal” event (or more formal) beginning after 6 PM, because such events often demand a step-up in formality (closer to evening informal).</li>
  <li>One-button or double-breasted suits. These garments tend to be more formal, and should be worn with a stiff or otherwise non-buttoned collar.</li>
</ul>

<p>Furthermore, if the collar on the shirt is too short, it will be unable to “contain” a tie, and is better worn tieless.</p>

<p>Here are things that would look great for the button-down-with-tie look:</p>

<ul>
  <li>American sack suits (J. Press, Brooks Brothers, Jos A Bank), or anything with a center vent</li>
  <li>The “all-American” navy blazer, and its not-all-American cousins</li>
  <li>Tweed (or otherwise rough-textured and/or patterned) sport coats</li>
  <li>American-stripe ties (right to left), repp ties, and foulard ties</li>
  <li>Casual ties: silk knit ties and non-silk ties</li>
  <li>Bowties</li>
</ul>

<p>As I stated before, use a four-in-hand with your button-down collars. This is simply because the collar provides little tie space, and thus a smaller knot should be used. Additionally, the button-down collar should not be ironed flat, but rather curve a little to display a “roll.” A collar’s ability to display this “roll” is often used to judge its quality.</p>

<p>Although the button-down shirt could be difficult to wear with a jacket and tie, it is very comfortable to wear and perhaps the best collar to be worn tieless. Thus, it is definitely reasonable to invest in a few.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>On Open Collars</title>
	  <link>//on-open-collars</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-07-13T13:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//on-open-collars</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="assets/images/tieless.jpg" alt="Tieless at an outreach event" /></p>

<p>I had the misfortune of running into a seemingly unsuccessful job interview at Starbucks today. The interviewee looked stumped by all the unimpressed interviewer’s questions. To add to the misery, he was wearing a short point-collar balloon-fit plaid flannel shirt, with the top button done up.</p>

<p>The first rule for wearing a button-front shirt is to <strong>leave the collar button open</strong> - not only is it more comfortable, it even looks better. In fact, if the collar rests higher up on the neck, unbuttoning the top two buttons may be necessary. Wearing a tieless shirt is inherently casual, and fastening all buttons adds unwanted rigidity. Moreover, when a shirt is worn with the collar buttoned, the space between the collar points is meant to be filled. Removing the tie from a buttoned collar without unfastening it leaves the collar looking oddly empty. This rule mandates that only certain collars are meant to be worn without a tie. For example, tab collars or pin collars, where both collar points are meant to be attached together to support a tie from the back, quite obviously shouldn’t be worn without a tie because it will render the collar attachment pointless.</p>

<p>The second rule is that <strong>the collar tips must be long enough to touch the shirt front</strong>. Otherwise, the collar would flap around awkwardly (or at the very least strangely float in midair) while the wearer moves – a look that is both sloppy and unprofessional. The button-down collar, in which the collar tips are affixed to the shirt front with buttons, constantly ensures the abidance of this rule, making the collar perhaps ideal for tieless wear.</p>

<p>Another rule regarding collars for tieless wear states that <strong>collars must be able to support themselves in the absence of a tie</strong>. This is pretty easy to understand – one wouldn’t want to wear a collapsed collar. One simple solution is starch, but unfortunately it makes the shirt fabric more susceptible to tearing. Another is to wear shirts with higher collars – such as the traditional American button-down and British-style spreads.</p>

<p>The perhaps final rule to wearing a shirt tieless is disputed and dependent on personal taste – <strong>there should always be ample spacing between the two collar points to distract from the necessity of a tie</strong>. This rule is based on the assertion that collar point proximity reminds the viewer that a tie is usually worn between those points, defeating the tieless look’s purpose. Though I’ve never found the forward-point collar to be ideal to be worn tieless and do prefer wearing a wide-spread collar tieless, I think this assertion on collar point spacing should be taken with a grain of salt. As long as a collar can be worn with the top button unfastened, its tips can touch the shirt front, and it can support itself without a tie, there is no reason why the said collar cannot be worn without a tie.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A Few Words on Socks</title>
	  <link>//a-few-words-on-socks</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-07-07T13:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//a-few-words-on-socks</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I’m not an expert on socks, but I know enough to not wear white athletic socks with my suits and black dress shoes. I even know not to wear black dress socks unless I’m wearing black trousers (which is a rare occurrence in the first place). Instead, a man’s dress socks should help connect one’s clothing to his shoes.</p>

<p>The often simplest interpretation of this rule is to wear socks in the same exact color as one’s trousers. This way, one’s trousers will effectively extend to literally “connect” with the shoes. This is standard procedure in menswear. Especially clear when worn with suits, this method continues the flow of one’s clothing from head to toe. Additionally, “lengthening” the trouser will also make one’s legs look longer, increasing the perceived height of the individual.</p>

<p>Another interpretation of the rule reads that the color of the socks should be somewhere in between that of the trousers and that of the shoes. This rule is used more often when lighter-colored trousers are worn with darker shoes, or vice versa. In those cases, matching the socks and trousers isn’t enough to connect the shoes and clothing, and instead a “progression” of different tones is needed. For example, wearing a light gray suit with black shoes will look better with medium-gray socks than either light gray or black.</p>

<p>The final “interpretation” of the socks rule draws another color from clothing from the upper body and either matches it entirely or complements it – similar to how one might wear a pocket square. This is seen as a subtle way to display stylistic enlightenment, and, especially in cases of complementation, should only be left to those spiritually enlightened, for a lapse in judgment may result in monstrosities similar to wearing black pants with white socks. Safe ways to implement the non-trouser-related method of choosing socks involves matching the jacket (when a contrasting sport coat is worn), such as wearing navy socks with a navy blazer, despite tan-colored khakis.</p>

<p>When a man dresses for non-athletic events, he should either show his full ankle or none at all – anything else is considered bad taste, if not somewhat disgusting. So, with respect to length – one should wear socks in the “over-the-calf” length. They minimize the chance that one’s ankles will ever show. Wool and cotton, with a dash of spandex and other elastic materials, are the most common materials for dress socks. I expect woolen socks to be warmer than cotton ones, but feel free to experiment and see for yourself.</p>

<p>As for white socks – they are acceptable, somewhat, in non-athletic menswear. If the overall ensemble is sufficiently light/bright in color (the trousers would ideally have a bit of white in them) and the shoes worn are not black, white dress socks (as in those made in silk, luxury cotton, etc.; not the elastic ones one wears with running shoes) may seem acceptable for the occasion. However, if you’re reading this blog, you probably should leave such experimentation to others more experienced in socks.</p>

<p><em><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/theenmoy/10882944303">Cover image by Theen Moy</a></em></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Last Well Dressed President</title>
	  <link>//the-last-well-dressed-president</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-05-25T03:58:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-last-well-dressed-president</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>President Obama wears a uniform of dark blue or charcoal suits with white or light blue medium-spread barrel cuff shirts and darker ties. The suits are mostly well-cut from Hart Schaffner Marx, a traditional American clothier, but they still look off-the-rack. Overall, President Obama looks just like another businessman – conservative and better than many of his poorly-dressed colleagues in Washington, but nothing special.</p>

<p>Bush 43 wore custom suits from Oxxford, a very traditional and high-range American tailor. Like the incumbent President, Bush II looked very conservative with his wardrobe of point-collar shirts and patterned ties, but was not exactly “exceptional” in any way.</p>

<p>Number 42, Bill Clinton, was a victim of his times, and fairly poorly-dressed. As reported from the New York Times, his suits were loose-cut to provide comfort, and had wide and low lapels and a low buttoning-point. The suits fit with Clinton’s personality, but also looked extremely sloppy. In fact, since the President liked his suits ventless, he often looked as if he was wearing a flour sack. Clinton’s point-collar shirts and loud ties did not help correct this sloppy image.</p>

<p>Since leaving office, President Clinton seems to have changed his style to be the exact opposite of that during his Presidency. Now, Clinton wears very well-tailored three-button (and often three-piece) European suits, complete with a very wide spread collar and a bright-colored tie knotted in a large half-Windsor. Formerly sloppy and humble, the former President now looks neat but also extremely elitist.</p>

<p>George H.W. Bush seems to be the last president to actually dress well.</p>

<p>Bush I’s style seems to have been inspired by his early days at Yale. He embodied the Ivy League look. His suits, always well-fit, were bought from J. Press, a menswear company founded on the Yale campus, and were distinctive for their three-roll-two structure (although the suit had three buttons, the top button was meant to be only decorative and mostly hidden). His shirts had point-collars and double cuffs – another reflection of his Yale heritage – and his ties were distinctively American. More importantly, the elder President Bush often wore a white linen pocket square – a great finishing touch to the already spectacular ensemble.</p>

<p>Most importantly, President George H.W. Bush was distinct from his time. At a time when lapels and ties were wide to “project power,” President Bush wore slim. Despite President Reagan’s full Windsor knots were popular, Bush always sported the traditional four-in-hand. In the late 80s and early 90s, when all aspects of menswear turned to favor power, the 41st President of the United States never shifted much from his Ivy Leagues – a dedication to timeless style.</p>

<p><img src="https://img.buzzfeed.com/buzzfeed-static/static/2014-07/21/12/enhanced/webdr08/enhanced-12604-1405961440-1.jpg" alt="Socks" />
Now that his career in politics is over, the former President is still embodying Ivy League style, but with more display of personal taste. Look at his brightly-colored socks – a subtle yet effective way to personalize an otherwise conservative ensemble.</p>

<p>George H.W. Bush was the last well-dressed President of the United States.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Dress Shirts that Every Man Should Own</title>
	  <link>//dress-shirts-that-every-man-should-own</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-03-24T17:05:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//dress-shirts-that-every-man-should-own</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Though I often find reasons to justify my own dress shirt purchases, I have to admit: for a person who doesn’t plan to wear a dress shirt on a regular basis and instead only for designated “business” or “business casual” events, two dress shirts are sufficient – a plain white dress shirt with a medium-spread collar and barrel cuffs and a light blue button-down.</p>

<h3 id="the-white-shirt">The White Shirt</h3>
<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/116Q_WHITE" alt="BB White Shirt" />
<em>A Brooks Brothers white dress shirt with a spread (Ainsley) collar and barrel cuffs.</em></p>

<p>The white shirt is an essential part of a man’s wardrobe, but surprisingly, it is not as versatile as it seems to be. Though the white color provides a “blank canvas” to not disturb any potentially loud and busy ties, it also creates a rather stark and undesirable contrast between the shirt and other pieces of clothing. In natural light and especially bright sunlight, this contrast is often excessive, and may attract much unwanted attention to the wearer and label him as “attention-seeking.” To counter this, men should avoid bright colored ties (yellows, greens, orange-red, etc.) when wearing the white shirt in daylight and opt for duller shades (navy, gray, burgundy, etc.) instead.</p>

<p>However, the white shirt is a necessity for more formal events, as no shirt can surpass white in terms of formality. Additionally, the white shirt is particularly useful in the evening. As colors are often blanched by artificial light sources, contrast provided by a white shirt can effectively “bring out” the colors needed to brighten a dull-seeming outfit.</p>

<p>A white dress shirt is essential for a man due to its usefulness in evenings and formality. For the same reason, a button-down collar is unsuitable because it has been traditionally reserved for casual shirts. For versatility, a medium-spread collar should be chosen, as it is the happy medium between wide English cutaways, which is often seen as boastful and attracts unwanted attention, and American forward points, which often look strange when worn tieless. Barrel (button) cuffs should be chosen over French cuffs, and the latter requires cufflinks and has connotations of arrogance.</p>

<h4 id="recommended-brands">Recommended Brands:</h4>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Brooks Brothers:</strong> the spread, or “Ainsley,” collar is an appropriate medium spread. Described by many as “indestructible.” In my experience, the collar sits slightly lower on the neck.</li>
  <li><strong>Charles Tyrwhitt:</strong> the “Classic collar” is fairly similar to Brooks’ Ainsley albeit slightly narrower, and the collar sits further up on the neck. the new semi-spread (“semi-cutaway” in British English) collars are also very versatile and business-appropriate, and are slightly further spread than its “classic” collars.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you don’t mind wearing a forward-point collar (slightly narrower than the medium-spread and unsuitable for tieless wear) or a semi-cutaway (slightly wider than the medium-spread, but has the connotation of being worn by attention-seekers):</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Tommy Hilfiger</strong> – the point collar is commonly seen, but the semi-cutaway is only available on certain fabrics. The shrinking on these shirts is significant, however, and the shirts seem to be giving away after a year.</li>
  <li><strong>Jos A. Bank</strong> – the “Point” and “Spread” collars refer to forward-point and semi-cutaway, respectively. The “Joseph” line refers to medium-spreads. Most Bank shirts are cut fairly large, and may not be suitable for younger, trimmer men.</li>
  <li><strong>Nordstrom</strong> – The house brand of Nordstrom is comparable to Jos A Bank in quality.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="the-blue-shirt">The Blue Shirt</h3>
<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/008E_BLUE?$bbproductimages$" alt="BB Blue Shirt" />
<em>A Brooks Brothers blue dress shirt with a button-down collar and barrel cuffs.</em></p>

<p>A classic Brooks Brothers oxford-cloth button-down collared shirt (OCBD).
Light blue is often more suitable than white for business environments. Though still light enough in shade to be worn with most white-shirt-appropriate ties, the blue shirt is dull enough to “absorb” brighter colors, and thus is suitable to be worn with ties in yellow, green, orange, and lighter shades of red. In daytime, it is often recommended by menswear consultants over equivalent white shirts.</p>

<p>Considering that the blue shirt should be in a more casual style to balance the formal white, the light blue dress shirt should have a button-down collar. Though originally reserved for sport, the button-down collar has been transformed by mainstream American clothiers and Ivy League students to be suitable for business wear. Thus, the blue button-down collar is suitable for most interviews and business events.</p>

<p>Additionally, the collar looks appropriate when tieless as well, and thus is more suitable for business-casual wear. When worn without a tie, the “curve” of the collar is aesthetically pleasing to many, and the buttons fixing the collar to the shirt body prevents the collar from flapping around. It is important to note, however, that the button-down collar may not be appropriate for business in Europe, where menswear styles remains quite traditional.</p>

<h4 id="recommended-brands-1">Recommended Brands:</h4>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Brooks Brothers:</strong> the inventor of the button-down collar is still widely recognized as the maker of the finest button-down collar shirts.</li>
  <li><strong>Land’s End:</strong> Lower price and quality than Brooks Brothers, but still excellent shirts. The collar points on these shirts are a bit short, and thus the shirts many not be as suitable to be worn with a tie.</li>
  <li><strong>L.L. Bean:</strong> Around the same price as Land’s End, but with higher quality.</li>
  <li><strong>Nordstrom/Jos A. Bank</strong></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="exceptions">Exceptions</h3>
<p><img src="http://static2.politico.com/dims4/default/33e8fbf/2147483647/resize/1160x%3E/quality/90/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fstatic.politico.com%2Fa3%2Fb9%2F558c187c474ab8460ff93388b4af%2F150924-john-boehner-gty-629jpg.jpg" alt="John Boehner" />
<em>Speaker Boehner’s shirt wardrobe seems to consist only of oxford-cloth button-down collared shirts. (Getty)</em></p>

<p>Though blue and white solids should be staples to any man’s wardrobe, the strict prescription of “spread collar barrel cuff” and “button-down collar barrel cuff” are by no means absolute. The Speaker of the House, for example, seems to wear only button-down collar shirts, and the style works well with his choice of American-cut suits and ties. Wear whatever works for you – just try not to break any rules.</p>

<p><em>Cover photo by Robert Sheie at www.menswear-market.com</em></p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Buttoning a Suit</title>
	  <link>//buttoning-a-suit</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-03-12T18:05:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//buttoning-a-suit</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3 id="history">History</h3>

<p>Back in the 19th century, suits were designed for all buttons of a suit to be buttoned. However, in the early 1900s, King Edward VII of Great Britain became too large in diameter to comfortably fit in a fully-buttoned suit. Thus, he began to leave the bottom button of his suit jacket and vest unbuttoned. To make the King feel better, his subjects also started to unbutton the bottom buttons of their suits and vests, and this trend eventually spread to the commoners and continues until today.</p>

<p>Ever since the mid-20th century, men’s suits have been designed so that the bottom button serve only as a decorative purpose – meant to be left unbuttoned.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-button">How to Button</h3>
<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/792M_NAVY_2?$bbproductimages$" alt="Two Button Suit" />
<em>A two-button suit from Brooks Brothers. Notice that the bottom button remains undone.</em></p>

<p>Currently, the two-button-single-breasted jacket is the most popular style for suit jackets and sport coats. On a two-button jacket, the top button is fastened, while the bottom is often left undone.</p>

<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/554K_BLACK?$bbproductimages$" alt="Three Button Suit" />
<em>A classic three-button three-piece suit from Brooks Brothers.</em></p>

<p>Taller individuals often prefer a three-button jacket, but it requires a more complex rule. The bottom button is never buttoned, the middle one is always buttoned, and the top button is sometimes buttoned. The buttoning of the top button depends on the cut of the suit. To “test” whether your three-button suit demands the buttoning of the top button, fasten the middle button and see whether the top button “closes” on its own. If the suit does, button the top button; if else, button only the middle button</p>

<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/MZ00002_BLACK?$bbproductimages$" alt="One Button Tuxedo" />
<em>A Brooks Brothers one-button peak-lapel tuxedo.</em></p>

<p>For one-button jackets, such as dinner jackets, the only button of the jacket should be always buttoned. However, there is no rule for single-breasted suits with more than three buttons. Button these jackets as you see fit.</p>

<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/MK00174_NAVY?$bbproductimages$" alt="Double Breasted Suit" />
<em>A modern double-breasted suit, again from Brooks Brothers.</em></p>

<p>All buttons of a double-breasted suit are traditionally buttoned. However, in recent years, it has become popular to unfasten the bottom row of buttons on a double-breasted suit with more than two rows of buttons. The latter is more suitable for modern double-breasted jackets.</p>

<h3 id="when-to-button">When to Button</h3>
<p><img src="http://twt-thumbs.washtimes.com/media/image/2015/01/16/e4a8205096ae68026b0f6a7067001b5c_c0-0-4289-2500_s885x516.jpg?1a1269fc2f8f7263683f4357c8d8a2e8cb4b6b03" alt="Obama and Cameron" />
<em>British PM David Cameron and US President Barack Obama wear their suits unbuttoned while sitting (AP Photo/Carolyn Kaster)</em></p>

<p>Appropriate buttons on a single-breasted jacket are fastened when standing and unfastened when sitting. Some who wear bespoke or otherwise well-fitting jackets keep their jackets buttoned while sitting to “show off” its tailoring. Additionally, many choose to button their jackets while on camera, regardless of posture, because a closed jacket often looks better on camera.</p>

<p>By tradition, a double-breasted suit is always fully-buttoned regardless of posture. However, the bottom row of buttons is sometimes unfastened when sitting to relieve stress on the suit’s buttons.</p>

<h3 id="vests">Vests</h3>
<p><img src="http://s7d4.scene7.com/is/image/BrooksBrothers/FM00211_GREY?$bbproductimages$" alt="Vest" />
<em>A Brooks Brothers vest, worn without a jacket.</em></p>

<p>Vests are similar to suits in buttoning etiquette – the bottom button is always unbuttoned per British tradition. So, technically, European vests could be buttoned fully, but the difference between British and European-cut vests is so little that it is safe to leave all vests’ bottom buttons undone. For more casual occasions, it might also be appropriate to undo the top button of the vest for symmetry.</p>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
