<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>zane@chairmanzian.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
   <description>Synthetic biologist, biomedical engineer, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more...</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Friends Don’t Let Friends Use Peasant Sticks</title>
	  <link>//peasantsticks</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-25T10:06:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//peasantsticks</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I first used a fountain pen in second grade, but it was only in late 2015 when I picked it up as a “hobby.” Since then, other than for writing on surfaces that absolutely will not tolerate liquid ink, I have seldom picked up a ballpoint or rollerball ink. In fact, I’ve joined some in the fountain pen online community in calling them “peasant sticks” (jokingly, of course).</p>

<p>So, naturally, I’ve started trying to convert my friends to this hobby – my birthday presents to them have shifted from cookies, ties, and pocket squares to fountain pens, almost exclusively. There are a couple fountain pens that I usually get for first time users.</p>

<h3 id="top-pick-jinhao-x750-with-a-custom-nib">Top Pick: Jinhao X750, with a Custom Nib</h3>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:40.2314814815% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BBV-m5Xwikc/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">My new fountain pen came in today! #Jinhao X750 Shimmering Sands with a #Nemosine Extra Fine Nib. #fountainpen #newpen #calligraphy #nib #extrafine</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-02-03T23:58:46+00:00">Feb 3, 2016 at 3:58pm PST</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>The pen that I give as presents the most often is the Jinhao X750, a Chinese-made fountain pen. I like it X750 for two main reasons – it is extremely affordable and still look “fancy.” The “Shimmering Sands” design, pictured above, is especially popular because of the subtle silver glitter on the barrel.</p>

<p>Another key appeal of the X750 is its modularity, and not just because of my training as an engineer. Unlike most modern pens, the X750 comes with a converter, which allows the writer to use bottled ink without dishing out extra cash. In addition, it accepts “standard international ink cartridges,” which means that it will be <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/ink-cartridges/c/26/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-long%2CTenant~Cartridge_Type%3Astandard-international-short">easy to find refills</a> for those who favor convenience. Diamine, J. Herbin, Kaweco, Pelikan, and many other ink manufacturers make cartridges that would fit in the X750, meaning that the pen’s user can find a wide variety of color choices without having to subject themselves to the messiness of refilling from a bottle.</p>

<p>Even the pen’s nib is standard and easy to replace – any “#6 nib” would be able to fit into the pen, which allows the user to change the width and style of their writing. This leads me to one of the drawbacks of the pen – the nib that it comes with is a bit flexible and somewhat bold/thick, which means that it might not be suitable for someone who is trying out fountain pens for the first time. Furthermore, the quality control on these pens tends to be variable. Because of this, I almost always replace the nib with a Fine or Extra Fine from Nemosine or Goulet Pens. This is not only an easier “starting point” for new fountain pen users, but will also show that you put in more time to customize the gift for the recipient.</p>

<p>This Jinhao X750 is widely available on <a href="http://www.ebay.com/sch/i.html?_from=R40&amp;_trksid=p2050601.m570.l1311.R1.TR5.TRC2.A0.H0.Xjinhao+x750.TRS0&amp;_nkw=jinhao+x750&amp;_sacat=0">eBay</a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/JinHao-X750-Silver-Fountain-Pen/dp/B00CC76756">Amazon</a> from Chinese sellers for under $5. You can also find the pen on <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-x750/c/97">Goulet Pens</a> for slight markup in return for better quality control and, if you’re in the United States, faster delivery. Perhaps somewhat ironic is that replacement nibs will probably run more expensive than the pen itself – <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/goulet-replacement-nibs/c/121">Goulet Pens nibs</a> run for $15, and <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/nemosine-nibs-parts/c/537">Nemosine nibs</a> $10.</p>

<h3 id="second-choice-platinum-preppy-eyedropper-pen-fine-nib">Second Choice: Platinum Preppy Eyedropper Pen, Fine Nib</h3>
<p><img src="assets/images/preppy.jpg" alt="Platinum Preppy" title="Platinum Preppy" />
More recently, I’ve started giving out Platinum Preppies, which are plastic, refillable but cheap-enough-to-be-disposable fountain pens from Japan. The chief appeal of this pen to me is its nib – a Japanese firm fine steel nib that reliably produces 0.38mm lines. Beginner fountain pen users tend to have an easier time with these firmer, finer nibs, and the Preppy is probably the cheapest pen you can find with that quality.</p>

<p>Admittedly, though, Platinum Preppies both look and feel cheap – their bodies are plastic, transparent, and covered in writing. However, these pens are in fact incredibly sturdy. Also, I find that people are more likely to use a Preppy than a fancier, metal pen, simply because the former seems less intimidating, thus facilitating smoother learning and transition.</p>

<p>Another good thing about the lack of metal in the pen body is that it can be converted into an “eyedropper,” which means that the entire barrel can be filled with ink if the threading is properly silicone grease-sealed and fitted with an O-ring (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XWLfr7TkRFU">many tutorials</a> show how to do this). I estimate that the pen can take around 3mL of ink, which would in turn supply a good 200 pages of writing. I usually eyedropper-convert Preppies before giving them out as gifts – in addition to showing the time and consideration I put into choosing the right ink, the ability to see ink sloshing around in the pen barrel adds novelty to an otherwise plain-seeming pen.</p>

<p>The Platinum Preppy is easy to find online, and usually come with an ink cartridge. You can usually find them in <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Platinum-Preppy-Rainbow-Fountain-Point/dp/B00IU3US7O">rainbow-colored 7-packs from Amazon</a> for around $15. <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-fountain-pens/c/280">Goulet Pens</a>, <a href="http://www.andersonpens.com/platinum-preppy-pens-s/1895.htm">Anderson Pens</a>, and <a href="http://www.jetpens.com/Platinum-Preppy-Fountain-Pens/ct/371">JetPens</a> also sell these pens individually, where they run for around $3-4 each.</p>

<h3 id="third-choice-pilot-metropolitan-fountain-pen-fine-or-medium-nib">Third Choice: Pilot Metropolitan Fountain Pen, Fine or Medium Nib</h3>
<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.7685185185% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ3xSfHgZ4j/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">Not bad for $15! The Pilot #Metropolitan Retro Pop in #turquoise dots, with a medium nib. #fountainpen #calligraphy #writing #nib #retropop #pilotmetropolitan</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-09-02T23:07:43+00:00">Sep 2, 2016 at 4:07pm PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>According to the fountain pen subreddit and many other online resources, the Pilot Metropolitan tends to be the first fountain pen that beginners buy to get into the habit. In some ways, the pen combines the best qualities of the Jinhao X750 and the Platinum Preppy – it has both an aesthetically appealing metal body and a reliable firm nib (~0.38mm for fine, ~0.5mm for medium). In other ways, it’s pretty much perfect out of the box.</p>

<p>Why, then, isn’t the Pilot Metropolitan number one on my list? I find that it’s a bit generic for a gift, and the only way you can really “customize” it is to pair it with ink samplers. So, I’d rather have this pen be the first that my friends would later purchase for themselves after becoming more involved in the hobby rather than gifting it to them.</p>

<p>The Pilot Metropolitan can be found online (<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Collection-Fountain-91111/dp/B00KRPFD96/ref=sr_1_1?s=office-products&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1480137789&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=pilot+metropolitan">Amazon</a>, <a href="http://www.jetpens.com/Pilot-Metropolitan-Fountain-Pens/ct/1706">JetPens</a>, <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/pilot-metropolitan/c/191">Goulet Pens</a>, <a href="http://www.andersonpens.com/pilot-metropolitan-pens-s/1888.htm?searching=Y&amp;sort=7&amp;cat=1888&amp;show=15&amp;page=1&amp;f-Fountain%20Pen=2448">Anderson Pens</a>), and usually sells for $15 for the pen, a cartridge, and a converter. However, if you’re looking to use bottled ink, I suggest buying a twist converter (CON-50 or CON-70), which will add a couple more bucks to the total price.</p>

<h3 id="other-good-choices">Other Good Choices</h3>
<p>Besides the Jinhao X750, Platinum Preppy, and Pilot Metropolitan, there are definitely more pens that you can buy for friends that you want to bring into the fountain pen hobby. For instance, the <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/jinhao-159/c/92">Jinhao 159</a> is very similar to the X750, and as a “tribute” to the <a href="http://www.montblanc.com/en-us/collection/writing-instruments/meisterstueck/115064-meisterstueck-platinum-line-149-fountain-pen.html">Montblanc Meisterstück 149</a>, it looks even more fancy-looking. The Lamy fountain pens are popular alternatives to Pilot Metropolitans, and the brand’s <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-safari/c/159">Safari</a>, <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-vista/c/168">Vista</a>, and <a href="https://www.gouletpens.com/lamy-al-star/c/154">Al-Star</a> models have triangular grip that show beginner users how to hold their pens in the correct orientation. I, however, never saw the appeal. My handwriting slants to the right, which means that I hold my pens at a different angle. The triangular grip, thus, disrupts my writing more than it helps.</p>

<p>Friends don’t let friends use peasant pens – what pens do you give your friends to start them on the hobby?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Fountain Pen Highlighters</title>
	  <link>//fp-highlighter</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-05T05:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fp-highlighter</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Recently I bought myself some <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/platinum-preppy-highlighters/c/288">Platinum Preppy highlighters</a>. Instead of using the free ink cartridges that came with the pen, I eyedroppered them with the matching <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/bottled-ink/c/14/?sortBy=productName%2Basc&amp;facetValueFilter=Tenant~Brand%3Anoodlers%2CTenant~Ink_Color%3Ahighlighter">highlighter inks from Noodlers</a>.</p>

<p>Pretty much, these pens are a hybrid of markers and fountain pens, since it sports the latter’s capillary action ink mechanism and the former’s easy-to-use tip. Filled with water-based yet fluorescent ink, it works quite well, easily drawing emphasis on written documents upon every streak.</p>

<p>The drawback of these highlighters, however, is that it’s quite “wet,” and that the ink can sometimes take awhile to dry atop the page. These properties, desired by users of fountain pens, might not be as useful for highlighters. I’ve had many instances where a too-slow stream with the highlighter not only bled through the back of a page, but stayed on the page long enough to stain the back of the previous page too.</p>

<p>Overall, I’m satisfied with the Platinum Preppy highlighter. Fountain pen fans should consider getting one to complete their entire fountain pen experience!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Happy Fountain Pen Day!</title>
	  <link>//fountain-pen-day</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-04T05:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//fountain-pen-day</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:52.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BMZ7HoFD2Uf/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-11-04T22:30:35+00:00">Nov 4, 2016 at 3:30pm PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>It’s the first Friday of November, and this means only one thing. Happy National Fountain Pen Day!</p>

<p>On that note, why isn’t there a National Pocket Square Day?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Moving Into Luxury Inks</title>
	  <link>//luxury-inks</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-04T12:46:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//luxury-inks</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div><p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;"><a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BItjdn2gc1c/" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;" target="_blank">A photo posted by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian)</a> on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-08-05T03:23:06+00:00">Aug 4, 2016 at 8:23pm PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>A bottle of <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/pilot-iroshizuku-kon-peki-50ml-bottled-fountain-pen-ink/p/PN69212">Pilot Iroshizuku Kon-Peki</a> ink arrived for me today, and I had a friend buy me a bottle of <a href="http://www.gouletpens.com/pilot-iroshizuku-yama-budo-50ml-bottled-fountain-pen-ink/p/PN69217">Yama-budo</a> from Japan, which I’ll get soon.</p>

<p>Pilot Iroshizuku inks sell at $35 for a 50mL bottle. The inks come in unique colors and “behave reliably” on many different papers. The bottle itself is intricately designed, with a “well” on the bottom that would fit a fountain pen, allowing the user to refill a pen from even the last drops of ink.</p>

<p>Though I didn’t pay retail price, the fact that I’m moving into this “luxury” category is nonetheless noteworthy. Just a few years ago, when I received a fountain pen as a high school graduation present, I shook my head at ink selections over $10. Back then, even seven dollars for a bottle of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/PARKER-Super-Quink-Bottle-S0037460/dp/B004YK4VHA">Parker Quink Black</a>, the cheapest fountain pen ink I could find, felt like too much to pay for stationary, and now I’m willing to pay multiple times as much.</p>

<p>Perhaps this is indicative of something, and I really need to find something less expensive to like…</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>My First Fountain Pen</title>
	  <link>//first-fp</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-25T09:25:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//first-fp</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Sometime in elementary school (for me, it was second grade), every Chinese kid would need to switch from writing with pencil to writing with a fountain pen - in every class. In addition to teaching us to write neatly, writing with a fountain pen was supposed to instill in us the value of doing things correctly the first time around. After all, ink, unlike graphite, was permanent, and showed our mistakes. So, if crossed-out sections or evidence of mysteriously ripped-out pages were found in our noteboks, we would be called up to the front of the class and berated for all to see.</p>

<p>Like any other eight-year-old having barely two years of handwriting experience, I dreaded writing with a fountain pen. Unlike the tip of a pencil, which writes in all directions, the fountain pen’s nib only put down ink properly at one angle. Furthermore, clumsy as I was, every night’s pen-refilling ritual left my hands dyed in blue. So, when we were given the opportunity to begin using gel pens (liquid ink, writes in all directions) halfway through third grade, I eagerly made the switch. I never thought I would ever voluntarily pick up a fountain pen again.</p>

<p>So, finding my old fountain pen from elementary schook during my trip to China was an strange yet interesting experience. I’m sure that eight-year-old Zian would never have imagined that thirteen years later, he had somehow become a fountain pen enthusiast, and own way too many bottles of ink and an unreasonable number of pens, but still feeling that he needed more. There was also a sense of nostalgia - coming back after finishing college and at the verge of graduate school, and seeing the equipment that helped me begin my academic journey all those years ago.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the child-sized pen no longer feels comfortable in my hands, and years of disuse has left it clogged with ink. Like many Hero fountain pens made in that era, it also now has a cracked section, which is now unable to attach to the barrel, and the cap no longer closes tightly.</p>

<p>But let it, in its own, particular way, serve as a memento for reflection and introspection for years to come.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
