<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>zane@chairmanzian.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
   <description>Bioengineer, synthetic biologist, regulatory consultant, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more...</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>How Useful Is a Striped Suit?</title>
	  <link>//striped-suit-useful</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-12-20T12:02:08-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//striped-suit-useful</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Long story short, unless you frequently chair boardroom meetings or work on Wall Street, it’s not.</p>

<p>Judging by the number of people I know with a striped garment as their only suit, my response will likely be surprising. Stripes are, after all, the most “classic” fabric pattern following solid weaves, and you really can’t beat vertical stripes when it comes to the slimming effect. So, what makes an otherwise classic and lengthening garment so useless outside those niche fields?</p>

<p>The rationale comes down to reputation and, as always, versatility. Stripes, particularly pinstripes, have been associated with business. By association, a striped suit is almost always a business suit, and is thus more or less only appropriate for wear for work and between the hours of 9 and 5. Sure, it’s perfectly appropriate for a sales meeting or for conducting business, but that’s about it. Striped suits are inappropriate for occasions that demand formality or festivity (i.e., look “fancy” instead of just “proper”). Similarly, they’re hard to dress down. The most obvious reason is that a striped suit cannot be worn separately, either as slacks or an odd jacket – either would look cut-off and isolated when worn without the other. I’ve also noticed that most striped suits are made to be fairly boxy and stiff, and any such suit would be difficult to wear without its full suite of accessories (i.e., not tieless).</p>

<p>The second reason why I find striped suits “useless” is their reputation – striped suits, especially navy suits with particularly bold stripes, are “power suits,” deeply associated with the ruthless ambition of Wall Street and seen to project it. Pair it with French cuffs, a bold tie, and some suspenders, and plenty of hair gel, and you will fit in at a Fortune 500 board meeting; but with all due respect, I suspect most readers of this blog won’t be anytime soon. While there are certainly certain workplaces where ruthless ambition is encouraged, for most professions, it’ll be met with suspicion. Don’t risk it.</p>

<p>I’ve owned two striped suits – gray with complementing blue stripes, which came in an eBay “lot” with a Hickey Freeman suit which I love and still frequently wear; and a navy with bold, light-blue chalk stripes, which I bought on impulse after seeing it discounted to sub-$30 after shipping.  I’ve given the gray one away. It was too stiffly “business” to dress up for special occasions, nearly impossible to dress down, and since I work in a business casual environment, fairly impractical for use. I still keep the navy one, which has particularly bold patterns, because it’s slightly more interesting. While it’s equally inappropriate for work, I’ve found it useful as a costume – I’ve worn it to a “simulated pitch session” during grad school where I needed to pretend to be a CEO, and also for Halloween, as a Wall Street banker. It draws attention and comments whenever I wear it, and, after all, isn’t that what a costume is about?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A Perfect Navy Blazer</title>
	  <link>//perfect-blazer</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-12-03T11:13:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//perfect-blazer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I own four blue sport coats. Two of them are gold-button blazers by Brooks Brothers, one single-breast and one double-breast; and the other being suit separates from T.M. Lewin, a three-button navy herringbone and a light navy mohair blend. I bought all of them on eBay over the last few years – spending no more than $40 per piece.</p>

<p>Recently, two of these jackets, coincidentally my daily rotation, have started showing irreversible wear – both have started “shining,” indicating fabric wear (i.e., cannot fix), and one’s lining is falling apart (i.e., not worth fixing). Now that I’m earning an income and no longer solely reliant on eBay deals, I have started considering replacing them with a single new jacket, possibly made-to-measure.</p>

<p>A good navy jacket, regardless whether it’s technically a blazer or just a sport coat, should be versatile, i.e., pairable with a wide variety of outfits. For my work environment, that means mostly tieless with both stiff and soft-collar shirts slacks or chinos. I’d also like to be able to use the jacket to dress up a pair of jeans without seeming like I forgot my suit trousers, and, of course, when the occasion calls for it, to wear it with most of my ties.</p>

<p>With that in mind, my “perfect navy blazer” would look something like this:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Medium navy, plain weave:</strong> I want the color and texture of the jacket to allow maximum versatility. This means a jacket dark enough to provide contrast against most odd trousers I’d be wearing but not so dark to look out-of-place without matching pants. A matte weave, or anything without an obvious sheen for that matter, would help keep the jacket look appropriately “not a suit.”</li>
  <li><strong>Soft shoulder and construction:</strong> a button-down collar, especially when open, looks sloppy and out-of-place with a stiff, structured-shoulder British jacket. I learned this the hard way, through putting my highly-structured T.M. Lewin jacket with countless button-downs, looking in the mirror, seeing something “off,” but not being able to figure out exactly why. Definitely not making that mistake again if I’m planning to pay &gt;$50…</li>
  <li><strong>Notch Lapels:</strong> I’ve experimented with peak lapels in both suits and sport coats. As sleek as they look, I find that I only wear them during specific occasions where I want to “stand out.” A navy blazer/sport coat is a garment that I wear on a daily basis. So, the standard, “blend in with the crowd” notch lapels will do. With respect to width, a classic 3 - 3.5” works best with my preference for larger spread or high-roll collars, as well as for any occasion requiring a tie.</li>
  <li><strong>3-roll-2, dark brown buttons:</strong> I’ve written an <a href="reconsider-3b">entire article</a> on my love for three-button, and the choice of brown over gold is one of versatility. Granted, traditional blazers demand gold, or at least metal, buttons, but this choice is limiting. On a purist perspective, the color of the button limits the color of other metals being worn as accessories (belt buckles, watches, etc.). On an aesthetics perspective, they simply look out of place when worn with jeans and, as such, fails the selection criteria.</li>
  <li><strong>Standard breast pocket, patch side pockets:</strong> patch side pockets are the best way to make a statement that a garment is casual, and since I’ll be using dark brown (i.e., suit-passing) buttons, having more casual pockets becomes a necessity. This would also avoid the annoying fact that jackets with flap pockets often end up with one tucked and one open by the end of the day from disproportionate use, and jetted pockets, which get rid of the flap altogether, simply look too formal.</li>
</ol>

<p>Combining these features with side vents and standard lining yields a jacket for work, play, and warmth – thus allowing me to wear it for 90% of my planned occasions. Not too casual or particularly formal, but definitely shows that you put thought into what you wear.</p>

<p>If you’re planning to wear the jacket to more formal occasions as a suit substitute, it certainly would make sense to choose flap pockets, metal buttons, and possibly even a smoother fabric (e.g., twill). But, I got this covered. My double-breast, gold-button Brooks Brothers blazer is about as formal as these garments get, and it looks to be able to withstand at least a few more years of wear. The other, lighter navy, almost indigo jacket will also get some rotation in the summer months, although I’ll probably get the buttons replaced with Mother of Pearl, first.</p>

<p>And thus begins the process of consolidating my wardrobe!</p>

<p>Update: It appears that both <a href="https://us.suitsupply.com/en_US/jackets/havana-navy-plain/C847I.html">SuitSupply</a> and <a href="https://www.spierandmackay.com/navy-hopsack-contemporary-fit.html">Spier and Mackay</a> sell ready-to-wear jackets that pretty much meet my criteria (through the three-roll-two is sold out at SM), if anyone is interested in matching blazers.</p>

<p><em>Cover image courtesy from Huntsman of Saville Row <a href="https://www.huntsmansavilerow.com/product/navy-serge-sb-blazer/">(source)</a>.</em></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Breaking a Navy Suit</title>
	  <link>//breaking-down-navy-suit</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-11-24T08:06:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//breaking-down-navy-suit</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>If you have one suit, make it a navy suit. It’s conservative, dressy, and easy to accessorize for festivity; and if you ever find the need to dress-up jeans or khakis, just wear the suit jacket by itself and voila – a navy blazer!</p>

<p>This is the argument frequently used to justify a navy “first suit.” It’s not wrong, but not every navy suit can be worn “broken down.”</p>

<p>The cardinal rule of navy sport coats is that they should absolutely not look like a lone suit jacket. After all, any sport jacket-involving ensemble should appear coherent, rather than giving the impression that you meant to wear a suit but forgot the pants. Since casual pants tends to be textured, sometimes even “rugged,” the jacket should likewise be rougher, at minimum matte. For a navy suit to be look good when as an odd jacket, it must pass for sport coat. In other word, it shouldn’t look much like a suit.</p>

<p>Subsequently, some have drafted suggestions accordingly that first-time suit buyers find an especially casual blue suit – essentially a blazer with “normal” buttons and matching pants – as to enable splitting. I disagree. The problem with this approach is that the best “blazer suits” aren’t great “first suits,” let alone “only suits.”</p>

<p>Take the <a href="https://us.suitsupply.com/en_US/suits/havana-blue-plain/P5176I.html?cgid=Suits&amp;prefn1=colorID&amp;prefv1=blue&amp;prefn2=fit&amp;prefv2=Havana">Havana navy suit from Suitsupply</a>, for example. While the fact that it has matching jackets and pants as well as buttons that aren’t metal makes it a “suit” by technicality, it is nonetheless casual. The soft shoulder construction, shorter jacket length, and patch pockets – all the features which give the suit the casual twist that helps it look “casual” as a sport coat – make it inappropriate for conservative attire (think wedding, funeral, interview, board room meeting, etc.). If you only own one suit, then I assume it is because you have no reason to wear it other than those rare occasions requiring formality. The supposed versatility of the Havana would thus be completely irrelevant.</p>

<p>Instead, my suggestion would be to seek the middle ground between blazer and suit. Get a suit in a solid, medium shade of navy (i.e., won’t pass for black, but getting there) with a slight texture (hopsack is good; avoid sharkskin because it “sheens” and looks out of place without matching pants).  As for styling, look for a classic two-button with vents and flap pockets, and make sure that the shoulder padding is light and not overly stuffed.</p>

<p>This configuration would give you a decently versatile suit, acceptable for formal occasions; with a jacket that can pass as a blazer when worn with jeans, khakis, or other slacks. Now, if I had a choice between one amazing suit like this and a decent suit and a blazer, at the same price, I’d go for the suit and blazer. But, if you have a budget and could only choose one, consider buying a navy suit that is ready to be split.</p>

<p><em>Cover: A navy pinstripe suit from SuitSupply <a href="https://www.grailed.com/listings/952226-Suitsupply-Napoli-Navy-Pinstripe">(source)</a>. Don’t ever wear this as a sportcoat.</em></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Conflicting Thoughts on French Cuffs</title>
	  <link>//frenchcuffs</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-25T06:10:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//frenchcuffs</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>“French cuffs,” also known as “double cuffs” to folks who call their fried potato strips “freedom fries,” are shirt cuffs that are folded back and fastened together with cufflinks in the “kissing” style, where the insides of the cuffs face each other. This style is more formal than barrel cuffs, although not as formal as “single-linked cuffs,” a “kissing,” cufflink-requiring style that doesn’t need a fold-back.</p>

<p>Most menswear enthusiasts think French cuffs are “too formal” to be worn with anything other than a suit. Even rules-shirkers like me would admit that French cuffs are simply not that convenient. The two-layer cuff style is cumbersome and look awkward when not under a jacket, and the need for cufflinks makes rolling up the sleeves difficult. On the other hand, though, French cuffs allow the wearer one more accessory to express his personality, and there are few things in menswear that look more elegant than a cufflinked-French cuff peeking out from under a well-tailored jacket.</p>

<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned="" data-instgrm-version="7" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:8px;"> <div style=" background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;"> <div style=" background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;"></div></div> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BBk0G3fQits/" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">French cuffs. #menswear #mensstyle #mensfashion #dappermen #dapper #menswatches #timex #eagledrive #natostrap #cufflinks #vintage #frenchcuff #quartz #divewatch</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A post shared by Zian Liu (@chairmanzian) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2016-02-09T18:15:37+00:00">Feb 9, 2016 at 10:15am PST</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async="" defer="" src="//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js"></script>

<p>Another point in favor French cuffs is that shirts with them are more often discounted or under clearance – probably because button/barrel cuffs are more versatile and thus sell better. I’ve gained from this fact, and have been filling my wardrobe with more and more French cuffed shirts – both in solids and patterns, never paying more than $25 apiece. Versatility was never a concern in school – everyone already knew me as the guy who dresses way-too-formal for the occasion, so nobody really batted an eye when I would show up to class wearing cufflinks under my navy blazer sleeve.</p>

<p>However, now that I’m entering the workforce, things are a bit different. As it turns out, French cuffs, because of associations with formality and elitism, are also as a status symbol in the professional world. At C-suite or partner-level, they’re certainly seen as appropriate, but people might frown on an associate-level person like me showing up with cufflinks, regardless of what kind of deal I might have gotten on the shirt.</p>

<p>So, I’m conflicted. There’s probably now a good quarter of my shirt collection that are high quality and in perfect, well-cared-for condition, that I won’t be able to wear regularly for at least the next few years. Do I regret purchasing them? Probably not – the amount I paid for them probably made them worth the purchase even if I wore them only once a decade. I guess I’ll just have to hope that I find engagements outside work soon enough that will make these shirts useful again.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Suiting Up for Interviews</title>
	  <link>//interview</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-14T08:34:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//interview</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It’s interview season for me, which means that for the first time in a while, I’ll be wearing a suit by necessity, not by choice. Certainly, dressing up frequently implies that I’ll probably be more comfortable with this “elevated formality” when compared to most of my peers, “interview attire” still is a little different from my personal style.</p>

<p>When I wear a suit for an event, I tend to pay attention only to coordination between different garments. This, when done with a general preference for subtle patterns and high contrast usually would yield very British-inspired ensembles – quiet suits and ties, patterned shirts, and an bright-colored pocket square. With respect to shoes, I alternate between pairs of longwing brogues in different shades of burgundy and brown. They not only provide a sense of sophistication, but also are easy to find well-cared-for, vintage, and affordable on eBay.</p>

<p>If I were to show up in these ensembles for an interview, I doubt I’ll raise any eyebrows (maybe if I wear my signature hot pink pocket square, it might be another story…). Even so, I still tend to err even more conservative, following the tried-and-true mantra of “two solids and a stripe.”</p>

<p>This, coupled with conservative business colors, only yields a few options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>A worsted woolen suit in solid navy or dark/charcoal gray.</li>
  <li>A cotton shirt in solid white or light blue</li>
  <li>A silk tie in burgundy or a shade of blue, with stripes (or some other small, conservative pattern)</li>
  <li>Black leather belt and shoes, preferably oxfords</li>
</ul>

<p>Pretty simple, right? Yes – if you have the luxury of having a wardrobe that has all these pieces, or the time and resources to buy or borrow them, but I’ve learned that most of my peers do not. How does one, then, make do with the pieces you have?</p>

<h3 id="suit">Suit</h3>
<p>Probably the biggest limiting factor. Solid blue or gray suits are ideal, but I find that a lot of my friends would instead own black suits (a cardinal sin in men’s business dress, mind you – read my first blog article), or some multi-striped monstrosity on sale at Men’s Wearhouse. My judgment aside, wear the darkest, least-patterned suit you have. If you must choose between a solid black suit and some multi-stripe with a more conservative color, go with the solid black – you can likely pass it off as navy or charcoal on a cursory glance.</p>

<h3 id="shirt">Shirt</h3>
<p>You really should have a solid white shirt and a solid light blue shirt. In addition to that, for interviews, you’d want a shirt that is well-fitting, has either a point or moderately-spread collar, and uses barrel cuffs. If this is not available, a button-down or wider spread collar should also work, but I’d avoid any shirts that has French cuffs – they might be seen as a “power play” garment. If you don’t have a “solid color” shirt, wear the one you have with the lightest background (preferably white) and least amount of patterns (no more than one additional color, in a simple stripe or checkered pattern).</p>

<p>Oh, another addition – I recommend against wearing a blue shirt against a black suit – the contrast just doesn’t look right. Blue suit and gray suits are, on the other hand, will be far more “forgiving.”</p>

<h3 id="tie">Tie</h3>
<p>Probably the most flexible part of this ensemble, but nonetheless still limited by the need to remain simple and “business-like.” A blue somewhere between royal and navy or a darker shade of red or burgundy works best, and I would find one with a small repeating pattern (pin-dots work well) or stripe, and stick away from solids because they are a tad “too” boring. A gray tie could work, but lighter shades or “silvers” might make you seem like you’re going to a wedding rather than an interview. Follow the rules on pattern sizing if any of your other garments are also patterned (match different patterns and vary like patterns).</p>

<p>I would be cautious, though, on wearing colors that are too “flashy” – that’s the bright reds, purples… anything that you would find on POTUS 45. On a similar note, stay away from shiny ties – a bit of sheen is good, but for interviews, you’d want to look more like POTUS 44 than the current one.</p>

<h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and Socks</h3>
<p>Nothing much to say here – wear black leather dress shoes and a matching leather belt. If you don’t have that, wear your darkest leather shoes or sneakers, and hope that your interviewer doesn’t look down. Your socks should match your pants, and if that doesn’t work, your shoes, and your ankle should be covered always. At no time is it appropriate it wear white, athletic socks, to a business formal interview…</p>

<p>If you have the luxury of choose, or are in the process of buying shoes, consider the following. Lace-up styles are better than slip-on loafers, and closed lacing systems (like Converse, but leather) are seen as more appropriate than open lacing. In addition, choose plain styles over complex patterns (e.g. brogues), and avoid overly square or overly pointy toe styles.</p>

<p><strong>And that’s it! These are all the pieces you’ll need to dress for an interview. Good luck!</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Reconsider the Three-Button Suit</title>
	  <link>//reconsider-3b</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-07-12T05:32:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//reconsider-3b</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>Harvey Specter from Suits, in a three-button suit</em></p>

<p>Once upon a time, not too long ago, men were expected to wear three-button suits – it’s just how things were, and in fact, JFK was considered a “radical” for opting for two-buttons during his presidency. Even in recent memory, two-button and three-button jackets were seen at similar frequencies, and considered “equally appropriate” for occasions of the same formality. However, three-button suits are now hard to find. When I visited a Hickey Freeman store last summer, I was surprised to hear that the maker no longer carried ready-to-wear three-button models, and that the style was only available made-to-measure.</p>

<p>Why did this formerly revered style disappear? All other things equal, a two-button suit will probably “more forgiving,” flattering more body types than its three-button equivalent, as well as feeling “less restrictive” when buttoned up. Even so, I still have a soft spot for the three-button style – and not just because I’m a “snowflake millennial from California” who likes to be different. A three-button coat, worn correctly, can work wonders to make a man look taller and slimmer.<br />
<img src="assets/images/st_always_never.jpg" alt="Sometimes, always, never" />
<em>Courtesy of Pinterest</em></p>

<p>The biggest “mistake” that I see on three-button suit wearers is fastening the buttons improperly – and this is an easy fix. As a reminder, the “rule” for such a suit is “sometimes, always, never,” from the top button down. To this, I propose a revision that the top button on a three-button coat should be closed “almost never.” This way, your three-button jackets looks virtually identical to a two-button, thus getting all its benefits. In addition, the presence of a third button could help you look taller – thank physics for visual illusions!</p>

<p>What, then, is the problem with buttoning both top buttons? On most such jackets, fastening the top button will leave almost no “space” between the lapels to “display” the shirt and tie, making the entire top half of the ensemble seem out of proportion. The lapels themselves will probably seem too short and too wide, all contributing to make the wearer seem short and stout and “misshapen” as well (Michel Anton’s words, not mine).</p>

<p>In what cases, then, can you safely button the top two buttons? This “style” works best on tall, skinny folks – on whom the proportions of a closed three-button suit would seem more reasonable. A suit with a lower top button, thus leaving more room to display the tie, and with narrower lapels, as to better “scale” the rest of the ensemble, would also help make the “top two” buttoning style make sense.
So, with that, go try on some three-button suits! If you could find one, that is.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Why I Got Into Suits</title>
	  <link>//why-suits</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-06-26T15:52:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//why-suits</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>If you walk through Berkeley, you will probably see more people in hoodies and sweatpants rather than jackets and ties. So, as a menswear enthusiast based in the Bay Area, I frequently get questions about what got me into suits and ties. So, I figured I’d write about this here.</p>

<p>Growing up, I spent a lot of time with my grandpa. As a former high school principal, Grandpa was accustomed to projecting authority through his clothes, and a wardrobe to match. Specifically, I remember he had four separate suits. The first, bought for cheap, was the suit he wore for going shopping to the open-air farmer’s market. The second, slightly more upscale, was for going to supermarkets (i.e. the indoor ones) and picking me up from school. A third suit would be for “general use,” such as photos, greeting guests, and attending social functions. The last suit was reserved for “special occasions only.” A 60th birthday gift from his children, the suit was from China’s then-top-designer and had a sticker price worth a few months of an average man’s salary. When I asked Grandpa to show it to me the last time I was back in Beijing, he informed me that the suit was safely locked away in a suitcase, and will only be brought out “when the occasion is right.”</p>

<p>However, I liked sweats and hated shopping as much as any other kid. It was an eye surgery during high school that finally exposed me to the more “respectable” parts of the menswear spectrum. After the procedure, doctors warned me to avoid pulling garments over the eye. This meant for a month post-surgery, I could only wear button-ups – I was forced to explore what I could do with them, and the habit eventually became stuck. I found that I was beginning to wear collared shirts by choice, rather than simply to protect my eye.</p>

<p>To make things arguably worse, I soon discovered the world of “thrifty menswear,” a community of men who seek treat purchasing menswear with the same attitude some have towards cars – “let someone else absorb the cost of buying new!” After all, quality, well-maintained suits or ties should last for decades. Furthermore, frequent sales and deals could bring the cost of new garments close to that of a “club fundraiser” t-shirt. As a result, my wardrobe grew, and we all know what happened next. Today, I own over 50 ties, write my own fashion blog, and teach workshops telling engineers how to dress for an interview.</p>

<p>Interesting how things go, isn’t it?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>What Color Tie Should I Wear?</title>
	  <link>//whatcolortie</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-03-14T14:45:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//whatcolortie</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Picking a tie can be difficult – they come in so many different colors, not to say different shades within the same color. Even between two ties of the exact same color, the texture of each fabric may come into play in figuring out which tie looks best with the rest of one’s ensemble.</p>

<h3 id="its-all-about-contrast">It’s all about contrast</h3>

<p>The traditional ideology picking color tones/shades is that the suit is darker than the tie, which is in turn darker than the shirt. This rule works, but really shouldn’t be taken that seriously. While “suit darker than shirt” is a tried-and-true rule, the interplay between other garments is more flexible, and can best be summarized as “contrast or exact match.”</p>

<p>This statement might sound a bit confusing at first – if two things either match or contrast, then… what are they? In essence, you should avoid wearing colors that are similar but not the same – for example, a white shirt with a pale-yellow tie or a navy suit with a dark-but-not-yet-navy blue tie. Why is this a problem? Think back to the last time you had to insert figures into PowerPoint. You were using a white template and your figure looked like it had a white background too, but once you overlaid them, you found that the two “whites” were different. Now there was an awkward, faint border around your figure – not contrasting enough to look intentional and just enough to be annoying.</p>

<p>Get the image now? Try to avoid that in what your wear.</p>

<h3 id="fill-in-the-colors">Fill in the colors!</h3>
<p><img src="https://www.sessions.edu/wp-content/themes/divi-child/color-calculator/color-wheel.png" alt="A color wheel" />
It’s hard to come up with a definitive rule of what colors work well together and what don’t. Other than the rules that black should mix with neither navy nor brown, most colors will work with each other. (Even navy/brown and black can be worn together tastefully.) You can use color wheel to find the best tie colors to contrast or harmonize with a given jacket or shirt, but let’s be honest – it will take forever.</p>

<p>If you’re lazy, you can wear colors that are known to work: blue and gray, blue and red or orange, purple or pink with navy or black, blue or purple and yellow, brown and tan, etc. An easy way to figure out what “works” is to see what combinations exist in nature – colors found in scenery, on plants, in insects or animals. I admit it might sound weird at first, but just think about it – when was the last time you described nature as “awkward?”</p>

<p>A “more advanced” technique is to have one garment match the secondary color in another garment. What does that mean? If you’re wearing a suit with blue stripes, a tie with the same color as the stripe seems to be a logical next step. The color of your hair or your eyes is another place of “inspiration. For instance, former Vice President Biden was frequently praised by stylists for wearing blue ties that matched the color of his eyes.</p>

<h3 id="want-to-stop-thinking-about-it">Want to stop thinking about it?</h3>
<p>Prefer the Mark Zuckerberg/Steve Jobs aesthetic of wearing essentially the same thing every day? There’s a way to do that with suits too. Solid navy and solid burgundy ties work with pretty much every suit and every shirt, and with that, you now have more time to worry about everything else going on in your life.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Is There Such a Thing As Too Much Blue?</title>
	  <link>//toomuchblue</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-11-21T14:06:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//toomuchblue</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I love the color blue - it’s probably my favorite - and I wear it a lot. I own three solid navy suits and three solid navy sportcoats, most of my dress shirts are in shades of blue or are white with blue patterns, a majority of my ties are blue, and of course I have plenty of blue other accessories. Blue is an easy color to incorporate into any business/classic menswear ensemble, but the ensemble I wore to a departmental banquet tonight got me thinking about whether there’s such a thing as “too much blue.”</p>

<p><img src="https://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/BN-LU083_1218ac_GR_20151218152241.jpg" alt="President Barack Obama" title="Obama in Tonal Ensemble" /></p>

<p>My ensemble wasn’t all that uncommon - navy suit, medium blue shirt, and navy dotted tie. In fact, President Obama has been wearing darker shirts in his blue-on-blue ensembles recently, creating an overall “tonal” look, but this doesn’t seem to work quite as well on me. I subscribe to the Alan Flusser’s school of thought that the contrast within a person’s clothing should seek to complement their natural contrast, which means that East Asians like me would look best with higher-contrast ensembles to go with the yellow skin and black hair. The suit-shirt-tie combo I wore, however, has very little contrast - practically playing between navy and medium blue. The low-contrast problem is exacerbated by the fact that the only color in play was blue - a cool color known for its tranquil, peaceful connotations. While good as a base for combining with other colors and patters, wearing an ensemble with too much blue, especially multiple pieces of similar hues, can function to wash out the wearer’s other features and make him supposedly “fade away.”</p>

<p>So, while my ensemble didn’t necessarily look “bad,” a lighter shirt, or even a patterned one, could have enhanced it. A tie with a bit more contrast - possibly with broader white stripes rather than the less conspicuous dots - would have also done the trick. I did try to add as much contrast as possible with my pocket square by wearing one with a black and white houndstooth, which I thought would provide both pattern and difference in color, but, looking back, a square with slightly more white probably would have worked better.</p>

<p>Blue in all of its shades are great colors for menswear, but be wary of overusing it. Careful management of contrast is necessary to prevent blue ensembles from fading away.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>The Tieless Suit</title>
	  <link>//the-tieless-suit</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-09T11:13:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//the-tieless-suit</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>Presidents Xi of China and Obama of the United States met yesterday at the Sunnylands Estate in California. The dress code of the event was “no ties,” to emphasize the casual and friendly nature of the talks, but both leaders still chose to wear conservative solid navy suits and white shirts. (Photo: Evan Vucci, AP)</em></p>

<p>Wearing a suit without a tie can cause controversy. Proponents of the look call it “executive casual,” referring to the ensembles preferred by company executives who do not need to conform to a dress code, but still wish to look elevated. Critics, however, dub the look “the Ahmadinejad,” referring to the unpopular former Iranian President, whose country forbids the wearing of a tie due to the garment’s implications of Western oppression.</p>

<p>For a long time, I was not a huge fan of wearing a suit without a tie. After all, it makes no sense why anyone would bother putting on matching jackets and trousers if he considers tie as too inconvenient. Aesthetically, though, there’s really no reason why a sport jacket and odd trousers could be worn tieless and a suit cannot. So, lately, I’ve been finding myself doing the exact same thing that I attacked viciously just years ago - putting on a suit, checkered shirt, and a brightly-colored pocket square, but leaving the tie at home.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-we-wear-ties-anyways">Why Do We Wear Ties Anyways?</h3>
<p>To remove a tie from an ensemble, it is first important to understand the purpose of a necktie. In addition to filling up the space below one’s neck and above the lapel, the necktie also serves to add color, slim the body, and provide so-called “balance” to the ensemble by “tying an ensemble together.”</p>

<p>For example, if I were to wear a navy suit and a white shirt, wearing a tie of another color would reduce the starkness of the contrast between the two colors, making the ensemble more pleasant-looking. Even a navy tie can serve to enhance the ensemble, for it will reduce the amount of white color displayed to reduce the amount of contrast seen.</p>

<h3 id="leaving-the-tie-at-home">Leaving the Tie At Home</h3>
<p><img src="http://cdn.abclocal.go.com/images/kgo/cms_exf_2007/news/state/9161881_1280x720.jpg" alt="Gavin Newsom" />
<em>Lt. Gov. Gavin Newsom wears a lighter gray suit for an open-collar shirt. (AP Photo/Noah Berger)</em></p>

<p>To accomplish the “executive casual” look, one should consider toning down the contrast between suit and shirt to trivialize the tie’s purpose of “tying together an ensemble.” One can do so by wearing a lighter colored suit (e.g. light gray and tan) or wearing a darker-colored and/or patterned shirt (solid white bad!). Also, one should consider choosing a suit with little “tie space” (higher buttoning point) to begin with, such as a more modern two-button or a three-button-roll. Note that though double-breasted and three-button suits tend to have smaller tie spaces, the suits tend to be more formal, and thus unsuitable for executive <em>casual</em>.</p>

<p>Some stylists suggested against the button-down collar for this look because the colloar is inherently casual and not sufficiently <em>executive</em> for “executive casual.” Instead, they would recommend a spread collar, which can stand upright without a tie and has uppity implications.</p>

<p>Stylists also warned against pinstripe suits due to their so-called formality, but I find no basis for their concerns because the pinstripe suit is not <em>formal</em>, but rather <em>for business</em>. Instead, I think the pinstripe suit is perhaps even ideal for this role - the stripes can both add color and serve a slimming and lengthening effect, both of which are usually the role of a tie. I would also add that the charcoal or dark gray suit should be avoided completely - both colors are too boring and too formal for executive casual.</p>

<p>Don’t forget a pocket square for a finishing touch!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
