<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>zane@chairmanzian.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
   <description>Synthetic biologist, bioengineer, biosafety advocate, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>BioEHS President Inaugural Address</title>
	  <link>//inauguration-address</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2014-12-12T12:18:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//inauguration-address</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I am honored and humbled to assume the Office of President of the Bioengineering Honor Society. For myself and on behalf of this club, I want to thank my predecessor for all she has done.</p>

<p>I want to recognize Anita for her role in the leadership, because she, not I, should have been the one becoming president today. Anita, you’ve given so much to this club - joy in a year as Social Chair and direction in a semester as EVP. We relied on you for each and every important project - two DWPs, the high school competition, a plethora of workshops, and countless socials. Your enthusiasm, your dependability, your natural and proven leadership - all these qualities made you the rock and backbone of BioEHS in this difficult time. I hope to be a worthy replacement of the great president you surely would have been.</p>

<p>For all of BioEHS - alumni, officers, members old and new - I want to apologize if this club has not lived up to your expectations. BioEHS needs to change after a year of stagnation, and it is the responsibility of this officer core to give the club the activation energy needed to revive it.</p>

<p>For we must make candidacy worthwhile to those who wish to join us, we must make membership meaningful for those who are a part of us, and we must make our actions useful for those around us.</p>

<p>My fellow bioengineers, fellow members of the Bioengineering Honor Society - the era of stagnation is over. Because today, the work to build a better BioEHS begins, and I hope to see all of you on the journey ahead.</p>

<p>Thank you, and good night!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
