<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>zane@chairmanzian.com</title>
   
   <link>mailto:zane@chairmanzian.com</link>
   <description>Synthetic biologist, biomedical engineer, STEM outreach organizer, political junkie, menswear enthusiast, fountain pen user, coffee addict, and more...</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> Zian Liu</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Keynote Address at Tau Beta Pi Candidate Meeting</title>
	  <link>//cm</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-09-22T13:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//cm</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     _As prepared for delivery._

I’m Zane, and I’m a Master’s Candidate in the Translational Medicine program joint between UC Berkeley and UC San Francisco. As an undergrad here and even now as a grad student, I’ve been really involved in Tau Beta Pi, and I’m here to answer the question, “why am I still here?”

Just three years ago, I was one of you, attending Candidate Meeting, just one floor up from here in the Woz. I joined TBP at the time because, as I suspect for the same reason many of you are here, I wanted it on my resume, and because I decided that the CM food was good and I wanted more.

But ultimately, it wasn’t the prestige or the food that kept me in TBP. I stayed in TBP because, in part, it no longer stood for “Tau Beta Pi” to me; it stood for “the best people,” and I’ll tell you three reasons why. 

The first reason I call TBP “the best people” is that it’s where I found my mentors, and this is an especially surprising statement for me because my interests are very unique – I was a bioengineer who also liked public policy. But you see – Tau Beta Pi is made up of top students from all disciplines engineering and has over 100 years’ worth of alumni who were once those students. So, it’s pretty likely that you can find someone who’s done what you want to do, and could get you where you want to be, even if you’re a special snowflake like me. 

The second reason TBP is “the best people” is that in addition to being mentors, they can also be your references for your next job. I’m learning this after sixteen long years in school and finally starting to look for jobs in the real world. In the job market of today, referrals from an employee might make the difference between getting overlooked or landing an interview. As it turns out, TBP alums can be found in every company you’ll probably consider applying to, and they’re more than happy to help you out.

The third reason TBP means “the best people” is that in this club, I found lifelong friends. During Veteran’s Day last year, two weeks before my senior project and first set of grad apps were due, I came down with pneumonia. Since I’m a serial procrastinator, I obviously hadn’t worked on my apps, and I tried to convince myself that despite my 104 degree fever, I was fine, and should work on my personal statements. It was a friend that I was only able to meet through TBP who took care of me, offered to bring me soup, and made me stop working and go to the hospital and get diagnosed, treated, and ultimately cured. She’s the reason I’m not only standing before you here tonight as a graduate student in one of the most prestigious translational medicine programs in the world, but also the reason I can stand before you at all.

TBP means “the best people” to me, and clearly, I found value in Tau Beta Pi.

Now, if you’re here, then you’ve been recognized as one of the best engineers in one of the finest universities in the world. All of you will succeed, regardless of whether you have the line “Tau Beta Pi” on your resume, but I encourage you to come and explore what TBP has to offer you.

This is where I found my mentors.

This is where I found my references. 

This is where I found my closest friends.

I’ll be around after, hopefully somewhere in the front of the food line outside, if you have any questions about what I just said. You’ll also find me at as many free food events this semester as I could make, and I hope that I’ll meet each and every one of you there.

Thank you.

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Cabinet Reshuffles</title>
	  <link>//cabinet-reshuffles</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-31T05:55:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//cabinet-reshuffles</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     When I was President of the Bioengineering Honor Society, I remember wishing for the power to “reshuffle cabinet.” This is a common practice amongst heads of government, such as prime ministers in parliamentary democracies and the President of the United States.

The idea is simple – the President or PM has the power to assign people in his cabinet to new official positions. This could be used to promote political allies or demote political rivals (which is probably the most common reason for reshuffles), or simply to optimize the governmental utility, putting the people with the most expertise or interest in each area in the positions that have influence on them. In a student group, this can work similarly – the President, or some constitutionally determined “executive,” can “move” officers around between positions. This can be appealing for two reasons.

The main reason is that new club members don’t always run for and get truly fitting positions; as these new officers get to know the club more, they may discover other roles which are more “appropriate” for their interests and talents, and a cabinet reshuffle allows them to enter that more appropriate portfolio instead of being “stuck” in their current one, without having to wait months for another election.

The second reason has to do with time – many officers discover halfway through their term that they are too busy with their schoolwork to perform their expected tasks. A cabinet reshuffle, in this case, can allow busy officers and less-busy officers to swap positions, allowing both to remain a part of the club while allowing work to get done.

There are, of course, counterarguments to implementing reshuffling. While promotions from favoritism may be a concern, I argue that it will likely be less prevalent than in government. Being offered some club title and, in conjunction, all the responsibilities associated with it, is not nearly as attractive as being offered the position of being third-in-line to the Presidency, and the social backlash will be high.

Another potential drawback of reshuffling is that members may not be as willing to become an officer if they don’t have the guarantee of being able to stay. Admittedly, some people are more driven by a position profile than the club when they run to be an officer (e.g. running to be an industrial relations position to get recruiter contacts, without much regard for the actual club). However, if an officer were so interested in their work, they should do well in it, and thus not need to be “reshuffled” to another position. So, this concern should be minimal as well.

Student clubs need flexibility among their personnel. More clubs should consider allowing their officers to move around – through cabinet reshuffles.
	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>No Longer Eat Alone</title>
	  <link>//no-longer-eat-alone</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-05-14T23:06:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//no-longer-eat-alone</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     _I wrote this essay in the beginning of my Freshman year of college. Now that I'm about to graduate, I'm posting this again for reflections._

It was 4:10 PM, on 26 February 2012, and in many respects, the day was just like any other day in Albany, California. The sky, as often is in late February, was clear, though the season of rain was within weeks of approaching. The street, commonly with only few cars on weekends, seems even emptier, for most residents have decided to retreat to their homes to watch the Academy Awards. The sun is setting, and the earth is quiet, save for the chirping of a few birds that have refused to migrate for the winter. My ride was late, and I was forced to walk to the community center alone.

I was dressed slightly more formal than usual – a dark gray overcoat, a navy pinstripe suit, a white dress shirt, a white pocket square neatly folded to show three corners, and a red tie with white and blue stripes tied in a symmetrical full Windsor knot – not exactly the correct attire for carrying two large stacked crates. One of the crates contained the official laptop of the Game Designing Club – a rusty Dell Latitude prone to blue screens – a camera, and a video camera. The other contained gifts for the banquet guests – 36 yellow bags, 36 packages of gummy bears, 36 candy bars, 36 handwritten thank-you notes, 36 thank-you pens, and 36 copies of my just-completed computer game – _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_.

I began _Legend of the Dragon Master_ as an eighth grader at Albany Middle School. I was free back then – lonely, in fact. I had long established my reputation as the class pariah through many years of being “weird,” and, expectedly, I had no friends. Instead, as I ate lunch alone every day in the corner of the blacktop, many came by to point at the “crazy genius,” whispering and giggling to their friends, wondering just what species I actually belonged to, since I definitely wasn’t human enough to fit in with them.

As I tore open the wrapping of the same sandwich in the same corner of the same blacktop, I wondered how I could change myself to be the same as my peers – how I could finally find someone to eat with during lunch. Yet, what seemed an easy task for most individuals was not simple to me. Through many years of isolation and confusion, I have established a reputation of being an aloof, eccentric, and outright weird child. My peers did not want to approach me, fearing that they’d become associated with the school’s outcast, and somehow become “uncool” as a result. Realizing that isolation would not help me in future years of schooling, I longed for friends – even just peers with whom I could chat and perhaps even have lunch. I longed for a moment that can reintroduce me to my teachers and classmates, convincing them that I am not insane – that I am one of them.

Through random searches on the internet performed during my long, boring, and friendless after-school hours, I discovered _Legend of Cao Cao_, an old Chinese game commonly modified by designers to create brand new productions. I was immediately interested. Having an immense interest within Chinese history and some experience with simple programming, I wanted to create my own game. It would be set in a futuristic environment oddly similar to that of Ancient China. The storyline would be based on a conflict between two forces: over time, the “just” force of the main character – I – would succeed in defeating the “evil” opposition and become a benevolent ruler of the world. As a creative twist, instead of taking figures from history, I planned to name characters after my classmates and teachers. To fit in with the theme of the game, characters would resemble warriors from medieval China, but would have characteristics exclusive of the people upon whom they were based. Yet, to realize my idea, I needed to do more than plan; I must start approaching others and tell them about my idea. With luck, they’d agree to be characters in my game. With luck, they’d be convinced that I’d be normal. With luck, they’d be my friend. With luck, they’d let me join them at lunch. With luck, _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ began.

Honks from a nearby car broke my daydream of remembering the beginnings of the production. I was one block away from the community center, and my friend Daniel, who had intended to drive me and my crates to the banquet site, had finally caught up with me. After a hastily mumbled excuse, he opened the door and let me in. 30 seconds later, we stopped before the building where my five-year journey with _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ will finally come to a close.

To my surprise, Daniel and I weren’t the first to arrive at the community center. Richard, the production’s coding director, had already waited there for ten minutes. With a tripod slung over his left shoulder, he complained about Daniel’s and my tardiness, and stated that he was always the first one to show up at any Design Team meeting. In fact, he was the first person to notice and support my creation of _Legend of the Dragon Master_ back in the eighth grade. Sitting across from me in Spanish class one day, Richard found his desk flooded with papers overflowing from an almost-toppled stack on my desk. Slightly annoyed, he picked a few up and tossed them over the invisible border between the two desks. “What the hell is this anyways?” He glanced at the cover of the overflowing folder. “Wait, you’re making a game?”

I tried to hide the document. I had not intended for anyone to know about my project yet. The ideas had not yet been fully developed. Everything was still a draft. Wanting the game to be a testament of my sanity, I feared that telling others about my novel ideas before their full development would effectively sabotage my goals. However, to Richard’s urging, I gave in and explained my plans. I expected him to mock my unorthodox ideas, but instead, he expressed interest in blending ancient China with modern society.  He said, “Let me help.” He became my first supporter and his integration in society attracted more peers to the game. In the next months, Spanish class was no longer awkwardly quiet, but instead, it was filled with sounds of Richard and I both working to recruit more characters and add more events to the storyline. “Put Mr. DeWall into your game!” he once suggested. “Add some scene in which he sings his song ‘No Puedo Dormir’ and gives all the enemies insomnia!” Our Spanish teacher was thus recruited as a character in the game, and in a month, half of our Spanish class had already been recruited into the game as characters, and the game became well-known across the school. My reputation improved and _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ was on the rise.

Daniel again awoke me from my imaginations, slapping his wrangled necktie in my face. He had a tendency to do that – reminding me of reality when my ideas become too abstract. As my associate producer, he was my most trusted adviser in the creation of the game. We began to speak a few months after the game became known to the public. I had stopped eating lunch in the corner of the blacktop, and instead had moved into classrooms – I took advantage of the computers there to perform the research needed to complete my game. By coincidence, Daniel was there one day, and we chatted randomly about swords in ancient combat as we chewed our sandwiches. To show him a Chinese sword, I turned on the computer and opened _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_, and he was immediately drawn – not to the scaly bitmap of the sword, but to my wish to create my own RPG. “Let me help you!” he offered enthusiastically, extending his hand. “I can help you test it, make it – do whatever you want.” As the production had grown to include a sizeable number of characters, I offered my hand as well, completing the handshake and accepting Daniel as my second co-worker.

Over the next few months, Daniel spent his Computer Science classes playing the game, and though the teacher did not quite appreciate it, I certainly did. Every day, Daniel would complete the levels that I had programmed, report bugs, and pester me for more stages to test. Now accompanied by an enthusiastic co-worker, I found myself working more efficiently. In four months, twenty stages of _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ had been completed. A month after that, we made the first custom _Legend of Cao Cao_ engine in English. Internet critics were stunned. They proclaimed it “the Dragon’s Miracle,” crediting me with the incredible feat, but, in reality, it was Daniel’s constant encouragement that had powered me to success, and ultimately, allowed me to host the celebration banquet of that day.

Shing– the music director– arrived next, and I was to go with her to the caterer and pick up our food. As she drove, I began to think of the night’s agenda. The banquet would begin with the arrival of guests, and proceed with a welcoming speech by Daniel. Then, accompanied by the men who helped me begin the production, I would formally announce that _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ was completed and released. Later, with numerous excessive formalities, I would thank the guests one-by-one for their help, and, ultimately, dedicate the game to a surprise guest and allow the guests to enjoy the rest of their meal without the sound of my voice droning on.

Shing had no idea that she was the surprise guest and dedicatee of my game, though it was not hard to predict that she would be on the top of my pick list. As the music director, she switched the collection of Chinese songs originally on the game soundtrack with a group of relevant songs in English – so that gamers could actually understand and enjoy the contents of the background music, rather than putting their computers on mute to avoid the ear-piercing screeches of a Chinese opera singer. In addition to her many contributions to the production, Shing had been a sister to me as well. Years ago, during English group projects, the oddly-numbered class would divide cleanly in two – with me as the lone remainder. At these moments, Shing would willingly take me into her group. Unlike my previous experiences with group projects, in which I would do all the work while other group members sat around and chatted, projects with Shing were always enjoyable. I never had to sit around and listen awkwardly to conversations in which I could not participate, for Shing worked to include me in group chats. Though I sometimes had trouble understanding references to popular shows, Shing would connect the conversation to a subject that I had an interest in. Later, she showed me Google Talk and Google Voice – two methods of keeping in touch with my newfound friends, finally allowing me to walk through the school as an integral part of society.

As I carried boxes of fried rice and chow-mein to the car, I continued to think about my change from the past years. As we drove back to the community center, I began to consider the speech – designed to be mostly impromptu – that I was about to give that night. Merely five years prior, I was a kid whom no person in his right mind wanted to approach. I was awkward and detached from society – though with high academic intellect, I had nearly no social ability. My partners in producing _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_ taught me differently. By paying attention to my plans, Richard told me that I had a thread of sanity. Through my work with Daniel, I grew confident in both myself and others’ willingness to accept me. With Shing’s help, I became integrated in the society around me, finally becoming that member of community that I had often longed to be. Others, too, aided me in my progress: there was Mr. Pressnall and the permission to be different, Profe and the ability to be liked, Nir and the process of self-presentation, Juneyoung and work efficiency, etc. etc. etc. Memories filled my mind as I walked to the lectern. Turning at the toe mark, I took a deep breath and looked ahead directly at the camera. Before me, 36 guests sat with plates of food before them. They were waiting for the signal:

>Ladies and gentlemen, it is my great honor and responsibility as Chairman of the Dragon’s Fury Game Series Design Team to announce the final release of _Dragon’s Fury: Legend of the Dragon Master_!

A thunderous applause filled the room, but only the youngest of children touched their forks, only to be quickly told to put them down by the parents. The guests were waiting for me, and I understood. I wrapped up my speech quickly and concluded with the game’s dedication to Shing and soon joined the guests as they began their long-awaited meal. As plastic utensils moved rapidly above plates of food and plastic cups came together in toasts, many guests were celebrating different things.

Some celebrated the end of a five-year project.

Others cheered at the realization of a seemingly impossible goal.

The kids liked that the old-looking-young-guy in the suit finally stopped talking and their parents finally let them start stuffing their food.

Yet, I celebrated a different change – simpler, more obvious:

**I celebrated that I no longer ate alone.**

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Presidential Address to 2015 BioEHSC</title>
	  <link>//bioehsc</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-04-04T01:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//bioehsc</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     _My speech at the opening ceremonies of the 2015 Bioengineering High School Competition, as prepared for delivery._

Thank you, and welcome to the second annual Bioengineering High School Competition, hosted by BioEHS at UC Berkeley!

As the Bioengineering Honor Society, we strive to advance bioengineering, both within UC Berkeley and in the community beyond. This effort begins with strengthening our membership, through workshops, networking events, and job and research opportunities. It continues with fostering the community, through service events and hosting the largest study group program on campus. And it culminates with events like this one - reaching out to elementary, middle, and high school students such as yourselves - and showing that as long as you have talent, as long as you have drive, as long as you want to solve problems in biology, you can be a bioengineer.

I say this knowing that bioengineering is not easy. It’s not supposed to be. To solve problems in human health and medicine, biology simply is not enough. Bioengineers must learn more to gain the set of tools needed to combat these concerns - from chemical engineering to patent engineering and from computer science to political science - but having knowledge isn’t enough.

Bioengineers must be undertake more responsibility because the subject of our work is not only chemicals and computers, but humans and other living things. The goal of our efforts is not just to save time or material, it is to save lives.

And there are challenges that come with this responsibility - FDA regulations, concerns in bioethics, societal impacts - nuances that may slow your progress. It will take longer for a bioengineer to succeed, but when you do, you feel a greater accomplishment. You are rewarded with not only wealth and fame, but also the knowledge that your efforts touched another human life. 

Responsibility. Character. Knowledge. These are some of the qualities of a successful bioengineer. Throughout today’s events, you will meet many of them - famed academics, researchers young and old, budding entrepreneurs, among others - and hear their perspectives on why bioengineering was right for them. After today, I hope you will gain a better understanding of what bioengineers do and what a career in biotechnology is like, and I hope that some of you will see the value that bioengineering holds for you.

Regardless of your outcome in this competition, I hope you find this event informative, and fun too. Regardless of which career path you later pursue, I hope that you will take today as an opportunity to meet and network with all the competitors gathered here - nearly 80 of you and with more on their way, because the next generation of the world’s leadership lie within people like you. Talk to each other; learn from each other; exchange ideas; help each other make the world a better place.

And we, here at BioEHS, will continue to work to bring more events like this to more young leaders just like you.

Thank you for your time, and let the bioengineering begin!

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>BioEHS President Inaugural Address</title>
	  <link>//inauguration-address</link>
	  <author>Zian Liu</author>
	  <pubDate>2014-12-12T12:18:00-08:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//inauguration-address</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     I am honored and humbled to assume the Office of President of the Bioengineering Honor Society. For myself and on behalf of this club, I want to thank my predecessor for all she has done.

I want to recognize Anita for her role in the leadership, because she, not I, should have been the one becoming president today. Anita, you've given so much to this club - joy in a year as Social Chair and direction in a semester as EVP. We relied on you for each and every important project - two DWPs, the high school competition, a plethora of workshops, and countless socials. Your enthusiasm, your dependability, your natural and proven leadership - all these qualities made you the rock and backbone of BioEHS in this difficult time. I hope to be a worthy replacement of the great president you surely would have been. 

For all of BioEHS - alumni, officers, members old and new - I want to apologize if this club has not lived up to your expectations. BioEHS needs to change after a year of stagnation, and it is the responsibility of this officer core to give the club the activation energy needed to revive it. 

For we must make candidacy worthwhile to those who wish to join us, we must make membership meaningful for those who are a part of us, and we must make our actions useful for those around us. 

My fellow bioengineers, fellow members of the Bioengineering Honor Society - the era of stagnation is over. Because today, the work to build a better BioEHS begins, and I hope to see all of you on the journey ahead. 

Thank you, and good night! 

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
